<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0"
>
<channel>
	<title>Amazing FBA &#8211; Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
	<atom:link href="https://amazingfba.com/10k" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://amazingfba.com/</link>
	<description>Amazon Coach &#38; Mastermind Convenor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:03:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>Blubrry PowerPress/11.9.11</generator>
		<atom:link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
	<itunes:summary>Do you sell private label or custom products on Amazon UK, USA or Europe? Or are you gearing up to do it? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you are struggling to grow sales, seeing profits erode and feel a long way from a sellable valuable business, we can help. If you&#039;re already killing it, why not grow faster and make even more cash? &lt;br /&gt;
Either way, you&#039;re in the right place. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our experts answer these questions and more - experts like Greg Mercer of Jungle Scout, Will Tjernlund, Manuel Becvar, Chris Green, Kevin King, and many many more. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whether you are trying to get Amazon product research right; help sourcing from China; optimizing Amazon listings; dealing with  Amazon PPC (aka Amazon ads) - we&#039;ve got you covered!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you&#039;re UK based and you want to sell in UK or USA; and if you&#039;re US based and you&#039;re curious about - or selling in - UK or Europe, you can&#039;t afford to miss the detailed insights you&#039;ll get.</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
	<itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>Michael Veazey</itunes:name>
	</itunes:owner>
	<copyright>&#xA9;Michael Veazey 2015-2022</copyright>
	<podcast:license>&#xA9;Michael Veazey 2015-2022</podcast:license>
	<podcast:medium>podcast</podcast:medium>
	<itunes:subtitle>Amazing FBA Amazon and ECommerce Podcast, for Amazon Private Label Sellers, Shopify, Magento or Woocommerce business owners, and other e-commerce sellers and digital entrepreneurs.</itunes:subtitle>
	<image>
		<title>Amazing FBA &#8211; Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
		<url>https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg</url>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/blog/</link>
	</image>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Careers" />
	</itunes:category>
	<googleplay:category text="Business"/>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Marketing" />
	</itunes:category>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Entrepreneurship" />
	</itunes:category>
	<rawvoice:rating>TV-G</rawvoice:rating>
	<rawvoice:location>London, England</rawvoice:location>
	<podcast:location>London, England</podcast:location>
	<podcast:podping usesPodping="true" />
	<rawvoice:subscribe feed="https://amazingfba.com/10k" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/ug/podcast/amazing-fba/id1030237683" spotify="https://open.spotify.com/show/32Cryk51sxVlF03B38UeoJ" amazon_music="https://music.amazon.co.uk/podcasts/3237ef11-0180-45a2-adff-2b4ab89267b5/amazing-fba-amazon-and-ecommerce-podcast-for-amazon-private-label-sellers-shopify-magento-or-woocommerce-business-owners-and-other-e-commerce-sellers-and-digital-entrepreneurs"></rawvoice:subscribe>
	<item>
		<title>Common eCommerce Mistakes And How To Avoid Them</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/common-ecommerce-mistakes-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15095</guid>
		<description>Running an eCommerce business can be a fantastic option these days - it’s what customers want, and it comes with plenty of benefits. However, just because it might seem like quite a simple thing to do as long as you’ve got a website and some social media happening, the truth is that there’s just as much to think about (and maybe more) as if you had a brick and mortar store, and it’s easy to make mistakes. 



The problem is that whereas in real life mistakes can often be rectified without too much damage done, when it comes to your eCommerce business, that might not be the case, and one mistake could spell disaster. With that in mind, here are some common eCommerce mistakes and how to avoid them - read on to find out more. 











Ignoring Mobile Optimization



It’s 2024, and most people shop on their phones, not on a computer (or at least they’ll browse on their phones and then make the final purchase on their computer), and if your website isn’t mobile-friendly, you’re essentially losing customers before they even get to the checkout page. Tiny text, slow loading times, challenging (to put it politely) navigation… it all causes frustration that could send your potential customers directly to your competitors. 



That’s why you need to use responsive design to make sure your website works properly on any device, whatever the size of the screen. It’s wise to test your website on a range of screen sizes from time to time to ensure it’s doing what it’s meant to do and so you can keep on top of things, just in case. 



Making The Checkout Process Complicated



Even if your site is great and a customer has chosen what they wanted and is ready to pay, you can still lose them right at the last second if you’ve got a complicated checkout experience - that could include things like too many steps, making them create an account, limited payment options, and so on. 



The fix is to simplify the checkout process as much as possible, so let people check out as guests if they want to, and always make sure you offer plenty of payment options so everyone is happy. And it has to be secure as well otherwise you’ll lose trust and that’s never a good thing. It’s a good idea to learn all about payment processing because the more you know, the better the checkout experience will be for your customers. 



Skipping Product Descriptions 



Have you ever landed on a product page and it’s just a photo and a price? If so, you’ll know that’s not enough - as a customer, you want more than that, especially if the price is a high one (but it’s the same principle for all products). After all, how are you going to know that what you’re buying is the right thing or worth the money if there’s no information? Customers will either just decide not to bother or they’ll go to another site to learn more, and probably end up buying there instead. 



That’s why you need to write clear, engaging, accurate, and detailed product descriptions - make sure you highlight key features, talk about benefits, and mention any specific unique selling points - and if you can include a video showing how it works, that’s even better. </description>
				</item>
	<item>
		<title>Make Confident business decisions: should you &#8220;Follow the numbers&#8221;?</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/make-confident-business-decisions-should-you-follow-the-numbers/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 05:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15059</guid>
		<description>Should entrepreneurs always &quot;Follow the numbers&quot;?



 Should you be led by the numbers in your business buying and selling decisions? Let&#039;s deal with that today.



Having previously bought various properties, I&#039;m now considering selling one A selling or buying decision around any asset, including property, or a business is a lot of the same sort of thing.



So you&#039;re buying an asset or selling an asset, which has a capital value, and then it will, if it works well, generate cashflow, sometimes negative if you get it wrong.



So should you be led by the numbers?



I&#039;ve been on a train with a Google sheet, working out the capital gains of selling a residential property versus keeping it.



What&#039;s interesting is how one arrives at decisions in business the nice thing about business is numbers guide you. Should they lead you? Should they guide you? Should you ignore them?



Let&#039;s take one extreme at a time and examine how it works.



Thesis: Ignore numbers (go with your gut)



Extreme number one is to ignore the numbers and go with your guts, follow your intuition.



There&#039;s a difference, between your guts and immediate instinct.



Instinctive reaction to pain causes short-term decisions



Running a business or owning property.



Can be painful. , there&#039;s legal liability people hassling you, spending your own money and time and regulations always increasing. Both in business and residential property. My experience in the uk, Amazon selling is not getting any less full of regulations particularly if you sell in the eu or you know, if you&#039;re looking at Amazon&#039;s legal changes.



Okay, so gut reaction might be just sell the damn thing because it&#039;s painful, but anything worthwhile can be painful. That&#039;s probably not a good plan.



Now, what about intuition? If your intuition says, it&#039;s hard work, but the pain is not worth the gain. You might be right. Intuition can, misguide us because we overrate immediate pain and underwrite future pain. So if we do something now that makes them the easy but cost you a lot of pain in the future, that&#039;s not a very rational way of making decisions.



Pure instinct or intuition has its dangers. So in the pure form, probably unwise, although one should not ignore one&#039;s intuition as an entrepreneur, 



Antithesis: Being led purely by the numbers



Here&#039;s version two, led by the numbers, not guided by the numbers, but just led by them.



The classic example of that mistake is in the the lockdown period or just after that, a lot of aggregators, private equity companies with a lot of money went out shopping for e commerce businesses based on Amazon. They made multiple mistakes, but one of them was based simply on following the numbers.



A lot of very smart people, many of whom I interviewed for the podcast at the time, were involved in that, but they didn&#039;t have Amazon common sense or e commerce common sense they were good at, number analysis. So they analyzed the numbers but what they didn&#039;t take out was any kind of common sense.



Why did the aggregators get it wrong in 2021-22?



If you look at the root cause of the massive increase in revenue and profits of e commerce businesses around 2019, 2020, was obvious. The pandemic and lockdowns particularly in the UK and US. Were extreme.



I was in the UK at the time, so yeah, that is in retrospect, I guess, very obvious what was, was going on there. Even at the time it wasn&#039;t rocket science to think there would be some kind of aversion to shopping in a physical location after the Pandemic, how much was going to be hard to call, but it wouldn&#039;t be zero. And there was going to be some reversion to spending discretionary earnings.



So consumer spending, you could spend on whatever that isn&#039;t just your rent or mortgage on some services such as entertainment, going out to pubs. Technically they&#039;re buying products, but they&#039;re kind of consuming them immediately. So it&#039;s kind of a service or other services like going to the cinema or going...</description>
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Should_entrepreneurs_always_Follow_the_numbers_.mp3" length="7596676" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:subtitle>Should entrepreneurs always &quot;Follow the numbers&quot;?     Should you be led by the numbers in your business buying and selling decisions? Let&#039;s deal with that today.    Having previously bought various properties,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Should entrepreneurs always "Follow the numbers"?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
 Should you be led by the numbers in your business buying and selling decisions? Let's deal with that today.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Having previously bought various properties, I'm now considering selling one A selling or buying decision around any asset, including property, or a business is a lot of the same sort of thing.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
So you're buying an asset or selling an asset, which has a capital value, and then it will, if it works well, generate cashflow, sometimes negative if you get it wrong.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
So should you be led by the numbers?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
I've been on a train with a Google sheet, working out the capital gains of selling a residential property versus keeping it.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
What's interesting is how one arrives at decisions in business the nice thing about business is numbers guide you. Should they lead you? Should they guide you? Should you ignore them?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Let's take one extreme at a time and examine how it works.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Thesis: Ignore numbers (go with your gut)<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Extreme number one is to ignore the numbers and go with your guts, follow your intuition.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
There's a difference, between your guts and immediate instinct.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Instinctive reaction to pain causes short-term decisions<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Running a business or owning property.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Can be painful. , there's legal liability people hassling you, spending your own money and time and regulations always increasing. Both in business and residential property. My experience in the uk, Amazon selling is not getting any less full of regulations particularly if you sell in the eu or you know, if you're looking at Amazon's legal changes.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Okay, so gut reaction might be just sell the damn thing because it's painful, but anything worthwhile can be painful. That's probably not a good plan.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Now, what about intuition? If your intuition says, it's hard work, but the pain is not worth the gain. You might be right. Intuition can, misguide us because we overrate immediate pain and underwrite future pain. So if we do something now that makes them the easy but cost you a lot of pain in the future, that's not a very rational way of making decisions.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Pure instinct or intuition has its dangers. So in the pure form, probably unwise, although one should not ignore one's intuition as an entrepreneur, <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Antithesis: Being led purely by the numbers<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Here's version two, led by the numbers, not guided by the numbers, but just led by them.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The classic example of that mistake is in the the lockdown period or just after that, a lot of aggregators, private equity companies with a lot of money went out shopping for e commerce businesses based on Amazon. They made multiple mistakes, but one of them was based simply on following the numbers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
A lot of very smart people, many of whom I interviewed for the podcast at the time, were involved in that, but they didn't have Amazon common sense or e commerce common sense they were good at, number analysis. So they analyzed the numbers but what they didn't take out was any kind of common sense.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Why did the aggregators get it wrong in 2021-22?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
If you look at the root cause of the massive increase in revenue and profits of e commerce businesses around 2019, 2020, was obvious. The pandemic and lockdowns particularly in the UK and US. Were extreme.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
I was in the UK at the time, so yeah, that is in retrospect, I guess, very obvious what was, was going on there.]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>608</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>608</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>7:55</itunes:duration>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>AI Finances for Amazon &#038; eCommerce Sellers</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/ai-finances-for-amazon-ecommerce-sellers/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15041</guid>
		<description>Imagine you&#039;re a thriving Amazon seller. You log in to Seller Central, download your settlement report, and receive your net deposit. But here&#039;s the catch: the numbers don&#039;t quite paint a clear picture of your finances. Amazon reserves make understanding your true profit, profitability, and cash flow a challenge.



Now, add multiple sales channels to the mix. The complexity grows exponentially, leaving you scrambling to reconcile data and make sense of your finances. This is where AI-powered accounting steps in, offering a lifeline for busy eCommerce brand owners.



[00:00] - Importance Of Clean Data For Business Owners[00:44] - Introduction And Context Setting[01:07] - Challenges Of Single-Channel Amazon Selling[02:10] - Webgility&#039;s Data Integration Process[03:02] - Multi-Channel Data Consolidation[03:38] - AI Assistant&#039;s Role In Data Analysis[04:34] - Automating Data Transfer To Accounting Systems[05:16] - Computers&#039; Efficiency In Numerical Calculations[05:59] - Common Issues In Data Integration[06:20] - Importance Of Consistent SKU Naming Conventions[07:31] - Webgility&#039;s Approach To Clean Data Setup[08:16] - Challenges Of Maintaining Consistent Data Practices[09:24] - Development Of AI-Powered Product Mapping Capabilities[10:40] - Difference Between Mechanical Systems And Intelligent Systems[11:58] - Two Approaches To Accounting Systems[13:39] - Impact Of Clean Books On Business Valuation[14:50] - Progression From Top-Line Focus To Profit And Valuation[15:17] - Introduction To Webgility&#039;s Services[16:10] - Webgility&#039;s Resources And Upcoming Webinars[16:39] - Importance Of Financial Preparation For Holiday Season[17:06] - Final Advice On Understanding Business Profitability[17:31] - Conclusion And Thank You



How AI Simplifies Your Accounting Nightmare



Webgility leverages the power of AI to transform your eCommerce finances. It can handle data from the most granular level (SKU) to your overall settlement reports, all presented in a user-friendly, centralized dashboard. Going beyond Amazon, Webgility integrates with other platforms and payment processors, offering a comprehensive overview of your finances, regardless of your sales channels.



Imagine logging in and having a virtual assistant at your fingertips, ready to answer your financial questions. AI-powered tools allow you to seamlessly connect your data with popular accounting software like QuickBooks. This enables you to record granular-level fees, identify trends over time, and gain valuable insights, all within Webgility or directly in your accounting software.



Clean Data: The Foundation for Accurate Finances



But before diving into AI, let&#039;s address the elephant in the room: clean data. Garbage in, garbage out is still a golden rule in the digital age. No matter how powerful AI is, it can&#039;t magically transform messy data into financial clarity.



The key to success starts with a well-organized product catalog. Develop a consistent SKU naming convention across all your channels. This seemingly simple step ensures accurate sales and profit tracking over time. Remember, inconsistent data leads to inaccurate reports, hindering your ability to make informed decisions.



While AI excels at processing unstructured data, it&#039;s not a miracle solution.



Here&#039;s where Webgility shines. It helps you get started the right way by offering features like:




SKU naming guidance: Webgility assists in establishing a consistent naming convention for your catalog.



On-the-fly account creation: Streamline the process by having Webgility automatically create clean accounts as you manage your business.



Professional onboarding: Webgility offers onboarding services to ensure your data is structured correctly from the get-go.




In some instances, AI can even help improve existing data. Webgility is constantly developing tools to analyze potentially flawed data, like identifying similar SKUs that may be duplicates. This can extend to customer and client data as well,...</description>
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/E02-AI_in_Accounting_for_Amazon_sellers-auphonic.mp3" length="16847515" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:subtitle>Imagine you&#039;re a thriving Amazon seller. You log in to Seller Central, download your settlement report, and receive your net deposit. But here&#039;s the catch: the numbers don&#039;t quite paint a clear picture of your finances.</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Imagine you're a thriving Amazon seller. You log in to Seller Central, download your settlement report, and receive your net deposit. But here's the catch: the numbers don't quite paint a clear picture of your finances. Amazon reserves make understanding your true profit, profitability, and cash flow a challenge.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Now, add multiple sales channels to the mix. The complexity grows exponentially, leaving you scrambling to reconcile data and make sense of your finances. This is where AI-powered accounting steps in, offering a lifeline for busy eCommerce brand owners.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00] - Importance Of Clean Data For Business Owners[00:44] - Introduction And Context Setting[01:07] - Challenges Of Single-Channel Amazon Selling[02:10] - Webgility's Data Integration Process[03:02] - Multi-Channel Data Consolidation[03:38] - AI Assistant's Role In Data Analysis[04:34] - Automating Data Transfer To Accounting Systems[05:16] - Computers' Efficiency In Numerical Calculations[05:59] - Common Issues In Data Integration[06:20] - Importance Of Consistent SKU Naming Conventions[07:31] - Webgility's Approach To Clean Data Setup[08:16] - Challenges Of Maintaining Consistent Data Practices[09:24] - Development Of AI-Powered Product Mapping Capabilities[10:40] - Difference Between Mechanical Systems And Intelligent Systems[11:58] - Two Approaches To Accounting Systems[13:39] - Impact Of Clean Books On Business Valuation[14:50] - Progression From Top-Line Focus To Profit And Valuation[15:17] - Introduction To Webgility's Services[16:10] - Webgility's Resources And Upcoming Webinars[16:39] - Importance Of Financial Preparation For Holiday Season[17:06] - Final Advice On Understanding Business Profitability[17:31] - Conclusion And Thank You<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
How AI Simplifies Your Accounting Nightmare<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Webgility leverages the power of AI to transform your eCommerce finances. It can handle data from the most granular level (SKU) to your overall settlement reports, all presented in a user-friendly, centralized dashboard. Going beyond Amazon, Webgility integrates with other platforms and payment processors, offering a comprehensive overview of your finances, regardless of your sales channels.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Imagine logging in and having a virtual assistant at your fingertips, ready to answer your financial questions. AI-powered tools allow you to seamlessly connect your data with popular accounting software like QuickBooks. This enables you to record granular-level fees, identify trends over time, and gain valuable insights, all within Webgility or directly in your accounting software.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Clean Data: The Foundation for Accurate Finances<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
But before diving into AI, let's address the elephant in the room: clean data. Garbage in, garbage out is still a golden rule in the digital age. No matter how powerful AI is, it can't magically transform messy data into financial clarity.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The key to success starts with a well-organized product catalog. Develop a consistent SKU naming convention across all your channels. This seemingly simple step ensures accurate sales and profit tracking over time. Remember, inconsistent data leads to inaccurate reports, hindering your ability to make informed decisions.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
While AI excels at processing unstructured data, it's not a miracle solution.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Here's where Webgility shines. It helps you get started the right way by offering features like:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* SKU naming guidance: Webgility assists in establishing a consistent naming convention for your catalog.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* On-the-fly account creation: Streamline the process by having Webgility automatically create clean accounts as you manage your business.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>607</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>607</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>AI Finances for Amazon &amp; eCommerce Sellers</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>17:33</itunes:duration>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Artificial Intelligence for Amazon &#038; eCommerce Sellers</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/artificial-intelligence-for-amazon-ecommerce-sellers/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15040</guid>
		<description>In today&#039;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, artificial intelligence (AI) has emerged as a game-changer for businesses of all sizes. For eCommerce sellers, AI offers a powerful tool to streamline operations, enhance customer experiences, and gain a competitive edge. This guide will delve into how SMB eCommerce businesses can leverage AI to optimize their operations, improve decision-making, and achieve sustainable growth.  



[00:00] - AI Benefits For Business Owners And Consumers[01:01] - Introduction To The 10K Collective Podcast[01:45] - Parag Mamnani&#039;s Background And Founding Of Webgility[02:36] - Challenges Of Multi-Channel E-Commerce And Inventory Management[03:34] - Financial Systems As The Cleanest System Of Record[04:47] - Complexity Of Pricing And Inventory Tracking[06:00] - AI Adoption In E-Commerce Organizations[07:16] - Early Days Of AI Integration In E-Commerce Platforms[08:30] - Difference Between Generative AI And Regression-Based AI[09:45] - Barriers For SMBs In Adopting AI Technologies[11:29] - AI For Small Business Operations[12:42] - Bifurcation Of AI Technology In Business[14:29] - Key Capabilities Of AI Assistants In Business Operations[15:52] - Importance Of Predictive Power In AI For Business Decisions[17:16] - Challenges In Forecasting Due To Unpredictable Events[19:12] - Impact Of Black Swan Events On Predictions[20:31] - Limitations Of Forecasting For Small Businesses[22:03] - Factors For Successful Future Predictions In E-Commerce[23:38] - Importance Of Blending AI With Human Intuition[24:53] - AI Assistant Inclusion And Learning From Customer Expectations



Understanding AI&#039;s Potential for eCommerce



AI, with its ability to analyze vast amounts of data and learn from patterns, can significantly benefit eCommerce sellers in various ways. By automating routine tasks, providing valuable insights, and personalizing customer experiences, AI can help businesses increase efficiency, reduce costs, and drive sales.



The Benefits of AI for eCommerce




Enhanced Efficiency: AI can automate repetitive tasks such as order processing, inventory management, and customer service, freeing up valuable time for more strategic activities.



Improved Decision-Making: By analyzing data and identifying trends, AI can provide valuable insights to inform business decisions, such as pricing, marketing, and product development.



Personalized Customer Experiences: AI-powered recommendation engines can offer tailored product suggestions to customers, increasing engagement and loyalty.



Optimized Operations: AI can help streamline supply chain management, improve inventory forecasting, and optimize logistics, leading to cost savings and improved customer satisfaction.




Leveraging AI for Operational Excellence




Inventory Management: AI can help optimize inventory levels by predicting demand, preventing stockouts, and reducing excess inventory costs.



Pricing Optimization: AI algorithms can analyze market data and competitor pricing to determine optimal pricing strategies, maximizing revenue and profitability.



Fulfillment and Logistics: AI can streamline the fulfillment process by optimizing shipping routes, reducing delivery times, and improving customer satisfaction.



Customer Service: AI-powered chatbots can provide instant customer support, answer common queries, and resolve issues efficiently.




Harnessing AI for Marketing and Sales




Personalized Marketing: AI can help create targeted marketing campaigns based on customer preferences, demographics, and purchase history, improving conversion rates.



Customer Segmentation: AI can segment customers into different groups based on their behavior and characteristics, allowing for more effective marketing strategies.



Predictive Analytics: AI can predict customer behavior and identify potential churn, enabling proactive retention efforts.




Implementing AI in Your eCommerce Business




Identify Your Goals: Clearly define the specific areas ...</description>
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/E01-AI_for_Amazon_ecommerce_sellers-auphonic.mp3" length="24428041" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:subtitle>In today&#039;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, artificial intelligence (AI) has emerged as a game-changer for businesses of all sizes. For eCommerce sellers, AI offers a powerful tool to streamline operations, enhance customer experiences,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
In today's rapidly evolving digital landscape, artificial intelligence (AI) has emerged as a game-changer for businesses of all sizes. For eCommerce sellers, AI offers a powerful tool to streamline operations, enhance customer experiences, and gain a competitive edge. This guide will delve into how SMB eCommerce businesses can leverage AI to optimize their operations, improve decision-making, and achieve sustainable growth.  <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00] - AI Benefits For Business Owners And Consumers[01:01] - Introduction To The 10K Collective Podcast[01:45] - Parag Mamnani's Background And Founding Of Webgility[02:36] - Challenges Of Multi-Channel E-Commerce And Inventory Management[03:34] - Financial Systems As The Cleanest System Of Record[04:47] - Complexity Of Pricing And Inventory Tracking[06:00] - AI Adoption In E-Commerce Organizations[07:16] - Early Days Of AI Integration In E-Commerce Platforms[08:30] - Difference Between Generative AI And Regression-Based AI[09:45] - Barriers For SMBs In Adopting AI Technologies[11:29] - AI For Small Business Operations[12:42] - Bifurcation Of AI Technology In Business[14:29] - Key Capabilities Of AI Assistants In Business Operations[15:52] - Importance Of Predictive Power In AI For Business Decisions[17:16] - Challenges In Forecasting Due To Unpredictable Events[19:12] - Impact Of Black Swan Events On Predictions[20:31] - Limitations Of Forecasting For Small Businesses[22:03] - Factors For Successful Future Predictions In E-Commerce[23:38] - Importance Of Blending AI With Human Intuition[24:53] - AI Assistant Inclusion And Learning From Customer Expectations<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Understanding AI's Potential for eCommerce<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
AI, with its ability to analyze vast amounts of data and learn from patterns, can significantly benefit eCommerce sellers in various ways. By automating routine tasks, providing valuable insights, and personalizing customer experiences, AI can help businesses increase efficiency, reduce costs, and drive sales.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The Benefits of AI for eCommerce<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Enhanced Efficiency: AI can automate repetitive tasks such as order processing, inventory management, and customer service, freeing up valuable time for more strategic activities.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Improved Decision-Making: By analyzing data and identifying trends, AI can provide valuable insights to inform business decisions, such as pricing, marketing, and product development.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Personalized Customer Experiences: AI-powered recommendation engines can offer tailored product suggestions to customers, increasing engagement and loyalty.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Optimized Operations: AI can help streamline supply chain management, improve inventory forecasting, and optimize logistics, leading to cost savings and improved customer satisfaction.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Leveraging AI for Operational Excellence<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Inventory Management: AI can help optimize inventory levels by predicting demand, preventing stockouts, and reducing excess inventory costs.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Pricing Optimization: AI algorithms can analyze market data and competitor pricing to determine optimal pricing strategies, maximizing revenue and profitability.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Fulfillment and Logistics: AI can streamline the fulfillment process by optimizing shipping routes, reducing delivery times, and improving customer satisfaction.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Customer Service: AI-powered chatbots can provide instant customer support, answer common queries, and resolve issues efficiently.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Harnessing AI for Marketing and Sales<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Personalized Marketing: AI can help create targeted marketing campaigns based on customer preferences, demographics, and purchase history,]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>606</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>606</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Artificial Intelligence for Amazon &amp; eCommerce Sellers</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>25:27</itunes:duration>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Launch Product on Amazon Using PPC Tactics</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/launch-product-amazon-ppc/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15031</guid>
		<description>The world of e-commerce thrives on innovation, and Amazon remains at the forefront. For brand owners, a successful product launch on this platform can be a game-changer. However, navigating the vast Amazon marketplace can be daunting, especially with limited resources. This guide equips you with the knowledge to strategically utilize PPC (pay-per-click) advertising to launch your product and propel your brand forward.[00:59] - Discussing Broader Expectations For PPC Strategies[01:26] - Subjectivity In Amazon PPC Strategies[01:56] - Example Of Keyword Strategy For Whiskey Products[03:14] - Separating Brands And Search Terms In Campaigns[04:01] - Gradual Introduction Of Different Ad Types[04:41] - Importance Of Consistency In PPC Strategy[05:18] - Balancing Patience And Action In PPC Management[06:39] - Importance Of Data And First Sales In PPC[07:28] - Periodic Review Of PPC Campaigns[08:06] - Adapting To Changes In The E-commerce Ecosystem[09:02] - Importance Of External Traffic For Amazon[09:48] - Balancing Organic And PPC Efforts[10:40] - Learning And Testing In Different Amazon Categories[11:09] - Impact Of Pricing On PPC Performance[12:09] - Importance Of Honesty And Transparency In Agency Work[13:00] - Understanding The Product And Target Market[14:31] - Overview Of Enzo Brands Services[15:37] - Enzo Brands&#039; Experience With Various E-commerce Platforms[16:15] - Enzo Brands&#039; Approach To Client Relationships[17:20] - Importance Of Brand Message On Amazon[18:20] - Keeping Things Simple And Understanding Basics



Understanding Amazon Ads Broad Match and Auto Campaigns



Amazon Ads offers various campaign structures, each with its advantages. Let&#039;s delve into broad match and auto campaigns:




Broad Match: This approach casts a wide net by capturing searches containing all or some of your keywords. While broad match can generate a high volume of impressions, it requires careful monitoring to ensure your ads reach the right audience.



Auto Campaigns: These campaigns leverage Amazon&#039;s algorithm to automatically identify relevant keywords for your product. While convenient, auto campaigns can be imprecise and necessitate ongoing refinement.




Striking the Balance: Broad Match vs. Targeted Keywords



Michael Kahn&#039;s Insight: Michael Kahn, an industry veteran with Enso Brands, emphasizes the value of starting with broad match campaigns. This initial broad approach helps you discover the keywords most likely to resonate with your target audience.



Beyond Long-Tail Keywords: Conventional wisdom dictates a heavy focus on long-tail keywords for Amazon PPC. However, this isn&#039;t always the golden rule. Depending on your product category, high-volume keywords like &quot;whisky&quot; or &quot;scotch whisky&quot; might yield excellent results.



Building a Robust PPC Strategy: Beyond Broad Match



While broad match offers valuable insights, a successful PPC strategy requires more than just initial experimentation. Here&#039;s how you can craft a results-oriented approach:




Sponsored Product Ads: This core PPC tactic showcases your individual products to targeted audiences based on keywords and product listings.



Harvested Keywords: Leverage data from broad or auto campaigns to identify high-performing keywords for future manual campaigns, allowing for more focused targeting.



Negative Match: Strategically exclude irrelevant keywords that generate clicks but don&#039;t lead to conversions. This helps you refine your targeting and save budget.



Branded Search Terms: Track branded search terms separately to assess brand awareness and avoid skewing overall campaign data.




Video and Headline Ads: Exploring Additional Options



While sponsored product ads are a strong foundation, consider incorporating video and headline ads for a more comprehensive approach:




Video Ads: These compelling visuals can effectively communicate your product&#039;s unique features and benefits, driving engagement and conversions.



</description>
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/02-Launch_Product_on_Amazon_Using_PPC_Tactics-auphonic.mp3" length="18480482" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:subtitle>The world of e-commerce thrives on innovation, and Amazon remains at the forefront. For brand owners, a successful product launch on this platform can be a game-changer. However, navigating the vast Amazon marketplace can be daunting,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
The world of e-commerce thrives on innovation, and Amazon remains at the forefront. For brand owners, a successful product launch on this platform can be a game-changer. However, navigating the vast Amazon marketplace can be daunting, especially with limited resources. This guide equips you with the knowledge to strategically utilize PPC (pay-per-click) advertising to launch your product and propel your brand forward.[00:59] - Discussing Broader Expectations For PPC Strategies[01:26] - Subjectivity In Amazon PPC Strategies[01:56] - Example Of Keyword Strategy For Whiskey Products[03:14] - Separating Brands And Search Terms In Campaigns[04:01] - Gradual Introduction Of Different Ad Types[04:41] - Importance Of Consistency In PPC Strategy[05:18] - Balancing Patience And Action In PPC Management[06:39] - Importance Of Data And First Sales In PPC[07:28] - Periodic Review Of PPC Campaigns[08:06] - Adapting To Changes In The E-commerce Ecosystem[09:02] - Importance Of External Traffic For Amazon[09:48] - Balancing Organic And PPC Efforts[10:40] - Learning And Testing In Different Amazon Categories[11:09] - Impact Of Pricing On PPC Performance[12:09] - Importance Of Honesty And Transparency In Agency Work[13:00] - Understanding The Product And Target Market[14:31] - Overview Of Enzo Brands Services[15:37] - Enzo Brands' Experience With Various E-commerce Platforms[16:15] - Enzo Brands' Approach To Client Relationships[17:20] - Importance Of Brand Message On Amazon[18:20] - Keeping Things Simple And Understanding Basics<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Understanding Amazon Ads Broad Match and Auto Campaigns<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon Ads offers various campaign structures, each with its advantages. Let's delve into broad match and auto campaigns:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Broad Match: This approach casts a wide net by capturing searches containing all or some of your keywords. While broad match can generate a high volume of impressions, it requires careful monitoring to ensure your ads reach the right audience.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Auto Campaigns: These campaigns leverage Amazon's algorithm to automatically identify relevant keywords for your product. While convenient, auto campaigns can be imprecise and necessitate ongoing refinement.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Striking the Balance: Broad Match vs. Targeted Keywords<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Michael Kahn's Insight: Michael Kahn, an industry veteran with Enso Brands, emphasizes the value of starting with broad match campaigns. This initial broad approach helps you discover the keywords most likely to resonate with your target audience.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Beyond Long-Tail Keywords: Conventional wisdom dictates a heavy focus on long-tail keywords for Amazon PPC. However, this isn't always the golden rule. Depending on your product category, high-volume keywords like "whisky" or "scotch whisky" might yield excellent results.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Building a Robust PPC Strategy: Beyond Broad Match<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
While broad match offers valuable insights, a successful PPC strategy requires more than just initial experimentation. Here's how you can craft a results-oriented approach:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Sponsored Product Ads: This core PPC tactic showcases your individual products to targeted audiences based on keywords and product listings.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Harvested Keywords: Leverage data from broad or auto campaigns to identify high-performing keywords for future manual campaigns, allowing for more focused targeting.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Negative Match: Strategically exclude irrelevant keywords that generate clicks but don't lead to conversions. This helps you refine your targeting and save budget.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Branded Search Terms: Track branded search terms separately to assess brand awareness and avoid skewing overall campaign data.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>603</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>603</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Launch Product on Amazon Using PPC Tactics</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>19:15</itunes:duration>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Amazon Advertising Strategy for Product Launches</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-advertising-strategy-product-launches/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15030</guid>
		<description>The world of e-commerce is booming, and Amazon remains a major player. For brand owners, a successful product launch on this platform can be a game-changer. But how do you stand out in a crowded marketplace, especially when resources are limited?



[00:00] - Introduction To The Podcast[01:31] - Introduction Of Michael Kahn From Enso Brands[02:13] - Michael&#039;s Background And Location[02:44] - Defining Launching On PPC[03:12] - Essential Preparation Before Launching[04:52] - Importance Of Competitor Analysis[06:28] - Understanding The Competitive Landscape[07:01] - Types Of Amazon PPC Ads[08:31] - Amazon Ads Team Innovation[09:14] - Focus On Video Ads For Product Launch[11:33] - New Partnership Between Amazon And TikTok[11:50] - Financial Expectations For Ad Spending[13:47] - Balancing Ad Spend And Patience[14:51] - Example Of Ad Spend Strategy Over Time[16:42] - Three-Month Timeline For Ad Strategy[17:46] - Gradual Adjustment Of Ad Spend[18:59] - Warning Against Abrupt Changes In Ad Strategy



Introducing Enso Brands and Michael Kahn:



This guide draws expertise from Enso Brands, a full-service agency for Amazon sellers. Led by industry veteran Michael Kahn, Enso offers brand acquisition, management, advertising expertise, and even warehousing solutions.



Launching on Amazon: New Products or Revivals



Your launch strategy will differ depending on whether you&#039;re introducing a brand new product or reigniting interest in a dormant listing. This guide tackles both scenarios, offering actionable tips to maximize your Amazon advertising impact.



Pre-Launch Checklist: Prep for Success



Before diving into PPC (pay-per-click) advertising, ensure a solid foundation for your launch. Here&#039;s what you need:




Know Your Target Market: Demography and psychographics are crucial.



Competitor Analysis: Identify direct and indirect competitors. Analyze their pricing, reviews, and ad strategies (including video usage).



Keyword Research: Conduct thorough keyword research to ensure your listing appears in relevant searches.



Listing Optimization: Craft compelling product descriptions with high-quality A+ images.



Vine Reviews: Consider leveraging Vine reviews for early, honest feedback.




Launching with PPC: A Powerful Toolset



Amazon offers a variety of advertising options to consider:




Product Ads: Showcase individual products to targeted audiences.



Branded Ads: Increase brand awareness and build recognition.



Video Ads: Effectively communicate your product&#039;s unique features and benefits.



Headline Ads: Enhance brand visibility, though conversion rates may vary.




Remember, Amazon provides tools to scale your spending, but consider utilizing third-party ad management solutions for added efficiency.



Optimizing Your Campaigns: What Works for Your Product



The key to successful Amazon advertising is finding what drives conversions for your specific product. Here&#039;s what Michael Kahn recommends:




Always A/B Test: Experiment with different approaches to identify the most effective messaging and visuals.



Embrace Video Ads: Consider video ads to showcase your product&#039;s unique selling points.



Start with Sponsored Products: These ads offer a good balance between conversion and cost efficiency.



Headline Ads for Brand Awareness: While conversion rates might be lower, they can be valuable for building brand recognition in certain categories.




Client Story: Video Ads Highlight a Unique Feature



Michael shares a client example where video ads were instrumental in showcasing a product&#039;s unique feature that wasn&#039;t easily conveyed through text descriptions. These compelling visuals helped differentiate the product from competitors and justify a higher price point.



ACoS, High Spend, and &quot;Bleeding Keywords&quot; During Launch



ACoS (Advertising Cost of Sale): Achieving the right balance between ACoS, high ad spend, and &quot;bleeding keywords&quot; (unprofitable keywords) is crucial during launch.



</description>
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/01-Amazon_Advertising_Strategy_for_Product_Launches-auphonic.mp3" length="18707434" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:subtitle>The world of e-commerce is booming, and Amazon remains a major player. For brand owners, a successful product launch on this platform can be a game-changer. But how do you stand out in a crowded marketplace, especially when resources are limited?    </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
The world of e-commerce is booming, and Amazon remains a major player. For brand owners, a successful product launch on this platform can be a game-changer. But how do you stand out in a crowded marketplace, especially when resources are limited?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00] - Introduction To The Podcast[01:31] - Introduction Of Michael Kahn From Enso Brands[02:13] - Michael's Background And Location[02:44] - Defining Launching On PPC[03:12] - Essential Preparation Before Launching[04:52] - Importance Of Competitor Analysis[06:28] - Understanding The Competitive Landscape[07:01] - Types Of Amazon PPC Ads[08:31] - Amazon Ads Team Innovation[09:14] - Focus On Video Ads For Product Launch[11:33] - New Partnership Between Amazon And TikTok[11:50] - Financial Expectations For Ad Spending[13:47] - Balancing Ad Spend And Patience[14:51] - Example Of Ad Spend Strategy Over Time[16:42] - Three-Month Timeline For Ad Strategy[17:46] - Gradual Adjustment Of Ad Spend[18:59] - Warning Against Abrupt Changes In Ad Strategy<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Introducing Enso Brands and Michael Kahn:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This guide draws expertise from Enso Brands, a full-service agency for Amazon sellers. Led by industry veteran Michael Kahn, Enso offers brand acquisition, management, advertising expertise, and even warehousing solutions.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Launching on Amazon: New Products or Revivals<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Your launch strategy will differ depending on whether you're introducing a brand new product or reigniting interest in a dormant listing. This guide tackles both scenarios, offering actionable tips to maximize your Amazon advertising impact.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Pre-Launch Checklist: Prep for Success<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Before diving into PPC (pay-per-click) advertising, ensure a solid foundation for your launch. Here's what you need:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Know Your Target Market: Demography and psychographics are crucial.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Competitor Analysis: Identify direct and indirect competitors. Analyze their pricing, reviews, and ad strategies (including video usage).<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Keyword Research: Conduct thorough keyword research to ensure your listing appears in relevant searches.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Listing Optimization: Craft compelling product descriptions with high-quality A+ images.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Vine Reviews: Consider leveraging Vine reviews for early, honest feedback.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Launching with PPC: A Powerful Toolset<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon offers a variety of advertising options to consider:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Product Ads: Showcase individual products to targeted audiences.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Branded Ads: Increase brand awareness and build recognition.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Video Ads: Effectively communicate your product's unique features and benefits.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Headline Ads: Enhance brand visibility, though conversion rates may vary.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Remember, Amazon provides tools to scale your spending, but consider utilizing third-party ad management solutions for added efficiency.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Optimizing Your Campaigns: What Works for Your Product<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The key to successful Amazon advertising is finding what drives conversions for your specific product. Here's what Michael Kahn recommends:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Always A/B Test: Experiment with different approaches to identify the most effective messaging and visuals.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Embrace Video Ads: Consider video ads to showcase your product's unique selling points.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Start with Sponsored Products: These ads offer a good balance between conversion and cost efficiency.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Headline Ads for Brand Awareness: While conversion rates m...]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>602</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>602</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Amazon Advertising Strategy for Product Launches</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>19:29</itunes:duration>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Amazon Tiktok integration (Amazon Newsday 10 Sep 2024)</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-tiktok-integration-amazon-newsday-10-sep-2024/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 05:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15026</guid>
		<description>Michael Veazey Welcome to Amazon Newsday. I&#039;m your host, Michael Veazey. Today, a couple of stories that are not in the last couple of weeks, but they were so important, we didn&#039;t want you to miss them.



Amazon Tiktok Integration Announced



Amazon TikTok integration.



On the 9th of August, Amazon and TikTok officially announced their partnership, enabling users to discover and purchase Amazon products directly within the TikTok app.



The integration allows TikTok users to see Amazon product recommendations on their For You feed. Users can link their TikTok and Amazon accounts through a secure one time setup process. Once accounts are linked, Amazon customers can then complete checkout within TikTok without leaving the app, providing a faster and more frictionless experience.



Users in the U S. who linked their accounts will see real time pricing, primary eligibility, delivery experts, and product details on select Amazon product ads in TikTok.



&quot;Project Handshake&quot;



This partnership is part of Amazon&#039;s Project Handshake, a broader Amazon strategy which aims to merge social media with e commerce.



Similar integrations have been made with platforms like Meta and Snapchat. For Amazon sellers, this integration could open up new opportunities to reach younger audiences through TikTok, potentially making sponsored display and DSP ads more effective.



This integration is initially launching only in the United States with no specific timeline provided for expansion to other regions. This partnership represents a significant step in integrating e commerce with social media, potentially reshaping online shopping behaviors and offering new avenues for brands to reach consumers.



Amazon required to recall unsafe products



Amazon has been required to recall unsafe products.



In a landmark decision, the U. S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, the CSPC, has ruled that Amazon is legally responsible for hazardous products sold by third party sellers through its Fulfillment by Amazon program. This July 29th ruling classifies Amazon as a distributor under the Consumer Product Safety Act, making it liable for over 400, 000 potentially dangerous items sold on its platform.



The case focused on products like flammable children&#039;s sleepwear, faulty carbon monoxide detectors and unsafe hairdryers.



As a result, Amazon must now develop plans to notify purchasers and the public about these hazards and provide refunds or replacements.



Wider implications for e-commerce sellers



This decision could have far reaching implications for other e commerce platforms, potentially subjecting them to similar notice reporting and recall obligations as traditional retailers. It underscores the CPSC&#039;s commitment to enforcing compliance across all



parties in the consumer product distribution chain.



Amazon plans to appeal the ruling, arguing that it had already taken swift action to warn consumers and offer refunds when notified of safety issues. However, the CPSC found these measures inadequate, emphasizing the importance of public notice for all potentially affected customers.</description>
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Amazon_Tiktok_integration_Amazon_Newsday_10_Sep_2024_.mp3" length="3627141" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:subtitle>Michael Veazey Welcome to Amazon Newsday. I&#039;m your host, Michael Veazey. Today, a couple of stories that are not in the last couple of weeks, but they were so important, we didn&#039;t want you to miss them.    Amazon Tiktok Integration Announced    </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Michael Veazey Welcome to Amazon Newsday. I'm your host, Michael Veazey. Today, a couple of stories that are not in the last couple of weeks, but they were so important, we didn't want you to miss them.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon Tiktok Integration Announced<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon TikTok integration.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
On the 9th of August, Amazon and TikTok officially announced their partnership, enabling users to discover and purchase Amazon products directly within the TikTok app.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The integration allows TikTok users to see Amazon product recommendations on their For You feed. Users can link their TikTok and Amazon accounts through a secure one time setup process. Once accounts are linked, Amazon customers can then complete checkout within TikTok without leaving the app, providing a faster and more frictionless experience.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Users in the U S. who linked their accounts will see real time pricing, primary eligibility, delivery experts, and product details on select Amazon product ads in TikTok.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
"Project Handshake"<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This partnership is part of Amazon's Project Handshake, a broader Amazon strategy which aims to merge social media with e commerce.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Similar integrations have been made with platforms like Meta and Snapchat. For Amazon sellers, this integration could open up new opportunities to reach younger audiences through TikTok, potentially making sponsored display and DSP ads more effective.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This integration is initially launching only in the United States with no specific timeline provided for expansion to other regions. This partnership represents a significant step in integrating e commerce with social media, potentially reshaping online shopping behaviors and offering new avenues for brands to reach consumers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon required to recall unsafe products<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon has been required to recall unsafe products.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
In a landmark decision, the U. S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, the CSPC, has ruled that Amazon is legally responsible for hazardous products sold by third party sellers through its Fulfillment by Amazon program. This July 29th ruling classifies Amazon as a distributor under the Consumer Product Safety Act, making it liable for over 400, 000 potentially dangerous items sold on its platform.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The case focused on products like flammable children's sleepwear, faulty carbon monoxide detectors and unsafe hairdryers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
As a result, Amazon must now develop plans to notify purchasers and the public about these hazards and provide refunds or replacements.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Wider implications for e-commerce sellers<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This decision could have far reaching implications for other e commerce platforms, potentially subjecting them to similar notice reporting and recall obligations as traditional retailers. It underscores the CPSC's commitment to enforcing compliance across all<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
parties in the consumer product distribution chain.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon plans to appeal the ruling, arguing that it had already taken swift action to warn consumers and offer refunds when notified of safety issues. However, the CPSC found these measures inadequate, emphasizing the importance of public notice for all potentially affected customers.<br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>601</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>601</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>3:47</itunes:duration>
		<podcast:transcript url="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Amazon-Tiktok-integration-Amazon-Newsday-10-Sep-2024.txt" language="en-gb" type="text/plain" rel="captions" />
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Skechers trainers &#8211; the power of serving one niche excellently</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/skechers-trainers-the-power-of-serving-one-niche-excellently/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15005</guid>
		<description>Trainers. Not a market that is obviously a winner for new products. If a client came to me with the idea of launching trainers, the names &quot;Nike&quot; and &quot;Adidas&quot; would come to mind as fierce competitors. And yet here is Skechers, making waves with a new trainer. But not just any trainer. And not just competing for the mass market. No, Skechers has created and expanded a wonderful niche market for itself selling trainers to people with a very specific need. One that Michael can speak to from personal experience!</description>
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Skechers_trainers-the_power_of_serving_one_niche_excellently.mp3" length="3055114" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:subtitle>Trainers. Not a market that is obviously a winner for new products. If a client came to me with the idea of launching trainers, the names &quot;Nike&quot; and &quot;Adidas&quot; would come to mind as fierce competitors. And yet here is Skechers,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Trainers. Not a market that is obviously a winner for new products. If a client came to me with the idea of launching trainers, the names "Nike" and "Adidas" would come to mind as fierce competitors. And yet here is Skechers, making waves with a new trainer. But not just any trainer. And not just competing for the mass market. No, Skechers has created and expanded a wonderful niche market for itself selling trainers to people with a very specific need. One that Michael can speak to from personal experience! <br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>599</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>599</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>3:38</itunes:duration>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Building Remote Teams for E-commerce</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/building-remote-teams-for-e-commerce/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15018</guid>
		<description>Kody Thompson, founder of WrkPod, isn&#039;t your average entrepreneur. He bootstrapped a web development company from a shoestring budget into a multi-million dollar powerhouse, generating over $5 million in profit. One of his biggest success factors? Building a high-performing team in the Philippines.



This guide delves into Kody&#039;s journey, exploring how he leveraged Filipino talent to achieve explosive growth. We&#039;ll uncover his recruitment strategies, team management philosophies, and the key benefits of outsourcing for ecommerce businesses.



Time Stamp



[00:00] - Introduction To The Podcast And Host Michael Veazey[01:09] - Welcome To The 10K Collective Podcast[01:26] - Introduction Of Guest Cody Thompson From WorkPod[02:02] - Early Stages Of Building A Remote Team[03:29] - Mental Leap To Get Started With Outsourcing[03:48] - Using Freelance Platforms And Virtual Staff Finder[05:03] - Setting Up A Physical Office In Dumaguete Philippines[05:50] - Renting Space From Silliman University[07:17] - Creating An Internship Program With University Students[08:57] - Navigating The Challenges Of Internship Programs[10:16] - Building Relationships With University Deans[11:56] - Streamlining The Hiring Process Through Internships[13:03] - Importance Of Local Relationships In Recruitment[14:29] - Introduction To WorkPod And Its Services[15:50] - Providing Support And Frameworks For Managing Remote Teams[17:03] - Common Management Mistakes With Remote Staff[18:58] - Learning From Management Mistakes And Experiences[20:24] - Challenges In Positioning Talented Employees[22:12] - Introduction Of VA Task Outsourcing Checklist[24:01] - Closing Remarks And Invitation To Join 10K Collective Mastermind



From Freelance Hustle to Global Success: The Power of Outsourcing



Kody&#039;s story begins like many others – a freelance graphic designer trading time for money. But Kody recognized the limitations of this approach. &quot;I wasn&#039;t getting paid when I was doing bookkeeping or social media,&quot; he explains. &quot;My value lies in design.&quot;



This realization sparked a pivotal shift. Kody started outsourcing administrative tasks, freeing him to focus on his core skills. This newfound efficiency fueled the growth of his web development company, propelling his annual revenue to a staggering $700,000 with a team of just 5-6 Filipino virtual assistants.



Building a Dream Team: Beyond Remote Work



While outsourcing tasks proved beneficial, Kody realized the limitations of a fully remote team. Managing talent spread across different locations posed challenges. The solution? Building a centralized team in the Philippines.



But where to start? Kody identified Dumaguete City, home to top universities brimming with tech talent. He secured office space near the university, forging partnerships with deans and establishing an internship program. This provided direct access to top students, many of whom transitioned into full-time positions after graduation.



Finding the Right Talent: Avoiding Common Mistakes



Outsourcing success hinges on finding and retaining skilled personnel. Kody highlights some of the most common pitfalls:




Assuming everyone learns like you: Different people learn in different ways. Tailor your training methods to ensure effective skills transfer.



Adaptability: Resistance to change is a common obstacle. Foster a culture that embraces evolution and continuous improvement.



Unreliable Payment: Not paying staff on time is a recipe for disaster. Develop a robust payroll system and prioritize on-time salary payments.



Inadequate Training: Throwing new hires into the deep end without proper training sets them up for failure. Invest in comprehensive training processes and establish clear procedures.




WrkPod: Beyond Recruitment, Building a Thriving Ecosystem



Kody&#039;s passion extends beyond simply connecting businesses with Filipino talent. WrkPod offers a comprehensive ecosystem to empower entrepreneurs:




</description>
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/E02-Building_Remote_Teams_for_E-commerce-auphonic.mp3" length="25110986" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:subtitle>Kody Thompson, founder of WrkPod, isn&#039;t your average entrepreneur. He bootstrapped a web development company from a shoestring budget into a multi-million dollar powerhouse, generating over $5 million in profit. One of his biggest success factors?</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Kody Thompson, founder of WrkPod, isn't your average entrepreneur. He bootstrapped a web development company from a shoestring budget into a multi-million dollar powerhouse, generating over $5 million in profit. One of his biggest success factors? Building a high-performing team in the Philippines.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This guide delves into Kody's journey, exploring how he leveraged Filipino talent to achieve explosive growth. We'll uncover his recruitment strategies, team management philosophies, and the key benefits of outsourcing for ecommerce businesses.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Time Stamp<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00] - Introduction To The Podcast And Host Michael Veazey[01:09] - Welcome To The 10K Collective Podcast[01:26] - Introduction Of Guest Cody Thompson From WorkPod[02:02] - Early Stages Of Building A Remote Team[03:29] - Mental Leap To Get Started With Outsourcing[03:48] - Using Freelance Platforms And Virtual Staff Finder[05:03] - Setting Up A Physical Office In Dumaguete Philippines[05:50] - Renting Space From Silliman University[07:17] - Creating An Internship Program With University Students[08:57] - Navigating The Challenges Of Internship Programs[10:16] - Building Relationships With University Deans[11:56] - Streamlining The Hiring Process Through Internships[13:03] - Importance Of Local Relationships In Recruitment[14:29] - Introduction To WorkPod And Its Services[15:50] - Providing Support And Frameworks For Managing Remote Teams[17:03] - Common Management Mistakes With Remote Staff[18:58] - Learning From Management Mistakes And Experiences[20:24] - Challenges In Positioning Talented Employees[22:12] - Introduction Of VA Task Outsourcing Checklist[24:01] - Closing Remarks And Invitation To Join 10K Collective Mastermind<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
From Freelance Hustle to Global Success: The Power of Outsourcing<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Kody's story begins like many others – a freelance graphic designer trading time for money. But Kody recognized the limitations of this approach. "I wasn't getting paid when I was doing bookkeeping or social media," he explains. "My value lies in design."<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This realization sparked a pivotal shift. Kody started outsourcing administrative tasks, freeing him to focus on his core skills. This newfound efficiency fueled the growth of his web development company, propelling his annual revenue to a staggering $700,000 with a team of just 5-6 Filipino virtual assistants.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Building a Dream Team: Beyond Remote Work<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
While outsourcing tasks proved beneficial, Kody realized the limitations of a fully remote team. Managing talent spread across different locations posed challenges. The solution? Building a centralized team in the Philippines.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
But where to start? Kody identified Dumaguete City, home to top universities brimming with tech talent. He secured office space near the university, forging partnerships with deans and establishing an internship program. This provided direct access to top students, many of whom transitioned into full-time positions after graduation.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Finding the Right Talent: Avoiding Common Mistakes<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Outsourcing success hinges on finding and retaining skilled personnel. Kody highlights some of the most common pitfalls:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Assuming everyone learns like you: Different people learn in different ways. Tailor your training methods to ensure effective skills transfer.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Adaptability: Resistance to change is a common obstacle. Foster a culture that embraces evolution and continuous improvement.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Unreliable Payment: Not paying staff on time is a recipe for disaster. Develop a robust payroll system and prioritize on-time salary payments.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>599</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>599</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Building Remote Teams for E-commerce</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>26:09</itunes:duration>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Build to Sell: Scale your Ecommerce Business to Exit</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/build-to-sell-scale-your-ecommerce-business-to-exit/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15014</guid>
		<description>Kody Thompson, founder of Wrkpod, understands the ecommerce journey. He bootstrapped a web development company from a $250 startup into a multi-million dollar powerhouse generating over $5 million in profit. Today, we&#039;ll dissect his &quot;build to sell&quot; approach, equipping you to scale your ecommerce brand for a successful exit.



Time Stamp



[00:00] - Introduction To The Podcast[00:20] - Michael Veazey Introduces The 10k Collective Mastermind[01:04] - Welcome To The 10k Collected Podcast[01:34] - Introduction Of Cody Thompson From WorkPod[02:24] - Why Cody Started A Graphic Design Business[03:41] - Transition From Solo Designer To Subscription Business[05:12] - Developing A Subscription Model For Websites[07:07] - Lessons From Niching Down And Customer Response[08:34] - Creating A Win-Win Business Model[09:46] - Path To Exiting The Business[11:26] - Decision To Sell The Web Development Company[13:48] - Finding A Buyer And Preparing For Sale[15:49] - Building A Business Ready To Sell[18:02] - Learning From Mentors And Decision-Making Process[19:44] - Negotiating Flexibility In Business Contracts[21:38] - Lessons On Utilization In E-commerce[23:11] - Things To Do Differently In An Exit[24:51] - Importance Of Business Community And Support[26:24] - Introduction To WorkPod&#039;s Business Model[28:58] - Free Checklist For Outsourcing Tasks[30:23] - Closing Remarks And Mastermind Promotion



Building Your Foundation: From Passion Project to Scalable Business



Many ecommerce ventures begin as passion projects. Kody initially offered freelance graphic design services to support his volunteer work. However, his vision evolved. Recognizing the limitations of selling time for money, he pivoted towards a subscription-based web development model.



The &quot;Aha&quot; Moment: Identifying a Lucrative Niche &amp; Building Recurring Revenue



Kody&#039;s turning point came when he realized the high cost of custom websites deterred small businesses. He observed a need within the fitness industry and pivoted again, creating website templates specifically tailored for gyms. This niche focus, combined with a subscription model, ensured recurring revenue and a scalable business.



Building a Business That Runs Without You: Systems, Documentation, and Delegation



Building to sell requires a business independent of your personal involvement. Kody achieved this by:




Systematizing processes: Creating clear workflows for all aspects of the business.



Detailed documentation: Documenting procedures for future reference and team training.



Clean financials: Maintaining accurate and up-to-date financial records.



Daily bookkeeping: Ensuring financial transparency for potential buyers.




The Power of Team: Building a Culture of Excellence



A strong team is fundamental to a thriving ecommerce business. Kody prioritized building a team he enjoyed working with, fostering a positive work environment. This translates into higher employee retention and a more attractive business proposition for potential buyers.



The Exit Strategy: Setting the Stage for a Lucrative Sale



Many entrepreneurs underestimate the importance of planning for an exit from the start. Here&#039;s why Kody built with the goal of selling:




Reduced reliance on personal time: A successful business generates revenue regardless of your daily involvement.



Reliable, recurring revenue: Predictable income stream attracts higher valuations from potential buyers.



Lower risk: A well-systematized business with a strong team mitigates potential risks associated with ownership changes.




Beyond Financials: The Importance of Preparations Beyond the Numbers



Kody built a business attractive to buyers in ways that go beyond just the bottom line. Here are two crucial considerations:




Data Room Readiness: Kody streamlined the due diligence process by having all necessary financial and operational documents readily available.



Strong Team: The quality and expertise of your team significantly imp...</description>
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/E01-Build_to_sell_Scale_your_Ecommerce_Business_to_Exit-auphonic.mp3" length="31092818" type="audio/mpeg" />
		<itunes:subtitle>Kody Thompson, founder of Wrkpod, understands the ecommerce journey. He bootstrapped a web development company from a $250 startup into a multi-million dollar powerhouse generating over $5 million in profit. Today,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Kody Thompson, founder of Wrkpod, understands the ecommerce journey. He bootstrapped a web development company from a $250 startup into a multi-million dollar powerhouse generating over $5 million in profit. Today, we'll dissect his "build to sell" approach, equipping you to scale your ecommerce brand for a successful exit.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Time Stamp<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00] - Introduction To The Podcast[00:20] - Michael Veazey Introduces The 10k Collective Mastermind[01:04] - Welcome To The 10k Collected Podcast[01:34] - Introduction Of Cody Thompson From WorkPod[02:24] - Why Cody Started A Graphic Design Business[03:41] - Transition From Solo Designer To Subscription Business[05:12] - Developing A Subscription Model For Websites[07:07] - Lessons From Niching Down And Customer Response[08:34] - Creating A Win-Win Business Model[09:46] - Path To Exiting The Business[11:26] - Decision To Sell The Web Development Company[13:48] - Finding A Buyer And Preparing For Sale[15:49] - Building A Business Ready To Sell[18:02] - Learning From Mentors And Decision-Making Process[19:44] - Negotiating Flexibility In Business Contracts[21:38] - Lessons On Utilization In E-commerce[23:11] - Things To Do Differently In An Exit[24:51] - Importance Of Business Community And Support[26:24] - Introduction To WorkPod's Business Model[28:58] - Free Checklist For Outsourcing Tasks[30:23] - Closing Remarks And Mastermind Promotion<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Building Your Foundation: From Passion Project to Scalable Business<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Many ecommerce ventures begin as passion projects. Kody initially offered freelance graphic design services to support his volunteer work. However, his vision evolved. Recognizing the limitations of selling time for money, he pivoted towards a subscription-based web development model.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The "Aha" Moment: Identifying a Lucrative Niche &amp; Building Recurring Revenue<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Kody's turning point came when he realized the high cost of custom websites deterred small businesses. He observed a need within the fitness industry and pivoted again, creating website templates specifically tailored for gyms. This niche focus, combined with a subscription model, ensured recurring revenue and a scalable business.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Building a Business That Runs Without You: Systems, Documentation, and Delegation<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Building to sell requires a business independent of your personal involvement. Kody achieved this by:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Systematizing processes: Creating clear workflows for all aspects of the business.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Detailed documentation: Documenting procedures for future reference and team training.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Clean financials: Maintaining accurate and up-to-date financial records.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Daily bookkeeping: Ensuring financial transparency for potential buyers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The Power of Team: Building a Culture of Excellence<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
A strong team is fundamental to a thriving ecommerce business. Kody prioritized building a team he enjoyed working with, fostering a positive work environment. This translates into higher employee retention and a more attractive business proposition for potential buyers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The Exit Strategy: Setting the Stage for a Lucrative Sale<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Many entrepreneurs underestimate the importance of planning for an exit from the start. Here's why Kody built with the goal of selling:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Reduced reliance on personal time: A successful business generates revenue regardless of your daily involvement.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Reliable, recurring revenue: Predictable income stream attracts higher valuations from potential buyers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>598</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>598</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Build to Sell: Scale your Ecommerce Business to Exit</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>32:23</itunes:duration>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
