<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0"

	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ecommerce Marketing - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
	<atom:link href="https://amazingfba.com/category/ecommerce-marketing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/ecommerce-marketing/</link>
	<description>Amazon Coach &#38; Mastermind Convenor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:59:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Amazing-FBA-new-logo-no-white-background-1-e1656858629506.png?fit=150%2C150&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Ecommerce Marketing - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
	<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/ecommerce-marketing/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<atom:link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
	<itunes:summary>Do you sell private label or custom products on Amazon UK, USA or Europe? Or are you gearing up to do it? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you are struggling to grow sales, seeing profits erode and feel a long way from a sellable valuable business, we can help. If you&#039;re already killing it, why not grow faster and make even more cash? &lt;br /&gt;
Either way, you&#039;re in the right place. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our experts answer these questions and more - experts like Greg Mercer of Jungle Scout, Will Tjernlund, Manuel Becvar, Chris Green, Kevin King, and many many more. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whether you are trying to get Amazon product research right; help sourcing from China; optimizing Amazon listings; dealing with  Amazon PPC (aka Amazon ads) - we&#039;ve got you covered!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you&#039;re UK based and you want to sell in UK or USA; and if you&#039;re US based and you&#039;re curious about - or selling in - UK or Europe, you can&#039;t afford to miss the detailed insights you&#039;ll get.</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
	<itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>Michael Veazey</itunes:name>
	</itunes:owner>
	<copyright>&#xA9;Michael Veazey 2015-2022</copyright>
	<podcast:license>&#xA9;Michael Veazey 2015-2022</podcast:license>
	<podcast:medium>podcast</podcast:medium>
	<itunes:subtitle>Amazing FBA Amazon and ECommerce Podcast, for Amazon Private Label Sellers, Shopify, Magento or Woocommerce business owners, and other e-commerce sellers and digital entrepreneurs.</itunes:subtitle>
	<image>
		<title>Ecommerce Marketing - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
		<url>https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg</url>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/ecommerce-marketing/</link>
	</image>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Careers" />
	</itunes:category>
	<googleplay:category text="Business"/>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Marketing" />
	</itunes:category>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Entrepreneurship" />
	</itunes:category>
	<rawvoice:rating>TV-G</rawvoice:rating>
	<rawvoice:location>London, England</rawvoice:location>
	<podcast:location>London, England</podcast:location>
	<podcast:podping usesPodping="true" />
	<rawvoice:subscribe feed="https://amazingfba.com/category/ecommerce-marketing/feed/" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/ug/podcast/amazing-fba/id1030237683" spotify="https://open.spotify.com/show/32Cryk51sxVlF03B38UeoJ" amazon_music="https://music.amazon.co.uk/podcasts/3237ef11-0180-45a2-adff-2b4ab89267b5/amazing-fba-amazon-and-ecommerce-podcast-for-amazon-private-label-sellers-shopify-magento-or-woocommerce-business-owners-and-other-e-commerce-sellers-and-digital-entrepreneurs"></rawvoice:subscribe>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">203239326</site>	<item>
		<title>Skechers trainers &#8211; the power of serving one niche excellently</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/skechers-trainers-the-power-of-serving-one-niche-excellently/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/skechers-trainers-the-power-of-serving-one-niche-excellently/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15005</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Trainers. Not a market that is obviously a winner for new products. If a client came to me with the idea of launching trainers, the names &#8220;Nike&#8221; and &#8220;Adidas&#8221; would come to mind as fierce competitors. And yet here is Skechers, making waves with a new trainer. But not just any trainer. And not just [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/skechers-trainers-the-power-of-serving-one-niche-excellently/">Skechers trainers &#8211; the power of serving one niche excellently</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/skechers-trainers-the-power-of-serving-one-niche-excellently/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Skechers_trainers-the_power_of_serving_one_niche_excellently.mp3" length="3055114" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Trainers. Not a market that is obviously a winner for new products. If a client came to me with the idea of launching trainers, the names &quot;Nike&quot; and &quot;Adidas&quot; would come to mind as fierce competitors. And yet here is Skechers,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Trainers. Not a market that is obviously a winner for new products. If a client came to me with the idea of launching trainers, the names "Nike" and "Adidas" would come to mind as fierce competitors. And yet here is Skechers, making waves with a new trainer. But not just any trainer. And not just competing for the mass market. No, Skechers has created and expanded a wonderful niche market for itself selling trainers to people with a very specific need. One that Michael can speak to from personal experience! <br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>599</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>599</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>3:38</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">15005</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dominate Your Amazon Launch: The $30K in 8 Weeks Influencer Strategy</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/dominate-amazon-launch-influencer-strategy/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/dominate-amazon-launch-influencer-strategy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14848</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Imagine launching your amazon product launch that&#8217;s brand new and achieving explosive sales within a short timeframe. Sounds like a dream, right? But what if we told you there&#8217;s a strategy that can help you achieve this – and it doesn&#8217;t involve a hefty advertising budget? This guide delves into a proven influencer marketing strategy [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/dominate-amazon-launch-influencer-strategy/">Dominate Your Amazon Launch: The $30K in 8 Weeks Influencer Strategy</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/dominate-amazon-launch-influencer-strategy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Episode_02-Make_30K_monthly_in_8_weeks_with_influencers_for_Amazon_product_launches-auphonic.mp3" length="23095587" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Imagine launching your amazon product launch that&#039;s brand new and achieving explosive sales within a short timeframe. Sounds like a dream, right? But what if we told you there&#039;s a strategy that can help you achieve this – and it doesn&#039;t involve a hefty...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Imagine launching your amazon product launch that's brand new and achieving explosive sales within a short timeframe. Sounds like a dream, right? But what if we told you there's a strategy that can help you achieve this – and it doesn't involve a hefty advertising budget?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This guide delves into a proven influencer marketing strategy specifically designed to create pre-launch buzz and propel your Amazon product launch to new heights. We'll explore how to leverage the power of influencers not just at launch, but in the crucial months leading up to it. By building anticipation and fostering a sense of community, you can ensure your product hits the ground running and achieves significant sales velocity.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Time Stamp<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00] - Introduction to the 10K Collective Mastermind[00:49] - Welcome to the podcast for Amazon sellers[01:13] - Focus on using influencers for product launches[01:22] - Applying influencer strategy to new product launches[01:52] - Building relationships with influencers before product launch[02:35] - Example of makeup brand building influencer relationships[03:36] - Benefits of early influencer engagement for product launches[04:13] - Comparison to film industry marketing tactics[04:36] - Addressing challenges with maintaining sales after initial launch[05:24] - Importance of newness in influencer marketing[06:06] - Strategy for scaling influencer relationships[07:27] - Analogy with scaling advertising campaigns[08:43] - Discussion on affiliate deals and commissions[09:40] - Explanation of the halo effect in influencer marketing[11:24] - Comparison to ACOS vs TACOS in Amazon advertising[12:37] - Benefits of generous affiliate commissions for Amazon brands[14:38] - Strategies for working with influencers without affiliate links[15:27] - The followers to customer funnel concept[17:03] - Approach to paying influencers based on proven results[18:44] - Efficient system for identifying effective influencers[19:15] - Information on Tomer's newsletter and resources[20:06] - Overview of Tomer's influencer marketing system<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The Long Game: Start Building Relationships 6 Months Before Launch<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Here's the secret weapon of this strategy: starting early. Don't wait until your product is ready to ship before reaching out to influencers. Ideally, aim to connect with them at least 6 months before your launch date. Here's why:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Emotional Connection: By engaging with influencers early, you allow them to become invested in your brand story. Document your product development journey and share it with them. This fosters a deeper connection and encourages them to become advocates for your brand.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Building a "Hot List" of Buyers: Through pre-launch influencer marketing, you can create a buzz that attracts potential customers. Encourage influencers to share snippets about your product and its development process. This creates a "hot list" of buyers who are already excited about your product before it even hits the shelves.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Case Study: The Power of Storytelling in Pre-Launch Buzz<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Let's look at a real-world example. Imagine a client developing a new makeup line for young girls. Due to unforeseen circumstances, the launch gets delayed by a year. However, the brand had already built relationships with over 200 relevant influencers. During the delay, they continued to share the product story and development journey with these influencers. This pre-launch buzz resulted in a phenomenal launch, proving the power of storytelling and early influencer engagement.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Influencer Marketing vs. Ads &amp; SEO: Consistency vs. Spikes<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
A common concern with influencer marketing is its perceived inconsistency compared to paid advertising or SEO.]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>24:03</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14848</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Influencer Marketing Beats Amazon Ads Every Time</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/influencer-marketing-beats-amazon-ads/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/influencer-marketing-beats-amazon-ads/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14844</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Influencer marketing is when you Imagine taking your brand new e-commerce store from zero to $30,000 in monthly sales within eight weeks. And achieving this feat without spending a dime on ads or content creation? Sounds like a dream, right? Well, for Tomer Hen, co-founder of Switch Supplements, this dream became a reality – all [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/influencer-marketing-beats-amazon-ads/">Why Influencer Marketing Beats Amazon Ads Every Time</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/influencer-marketing-beats-amazon-ads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Episode_01_influencer_relationships_instead_of_Amazon_ads-auphonic.mp3" length="23872573" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Influencer marketing is when you Imagine taking your brand new e-commerce store from zero to $30,000 in monthly sales within eight weeks. And achieving this feat without spending a dime on ads or content creation? Sounds like a dream, right? Well,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Influencer marketing is when you Imagine taking your brand new e-commerce store from zero to $30,000 in monthly sales within eight weeks. And achieving this feat without spending a dime on ads or content creation? Sounds like a dream, right? Well, for Tomer Hen, co-founder of Switch Supplements, this dream became a reality – all thanks to the power of influencer marketing.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
In this guide, we'll delve into Tomer's proven strategies to help you leverage influencer marketing and scale your e-commerce brand without breaking the bank. We'll explore the key differences between influencers and affiliates, understand why upfront payments might not be the best approach, and discover how to build authentic relationships with creators who can truly champion your brand.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Time Stamp<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00] - Introduction to influencer marketing without ads[01:34] - Defining influencers and affiliates[02:55] - Example of successful influencer marketing campaign[04:21] - Advantages of influencer marketing over paid ads[05:55] - Importance of identifying ideal influencers[07:15] - Finding high purchase intent influencers[09:10] - Process of identifying niche influencers[11:10] - Tactics for finding influencers for specific products[13:02] - Importance of brand representation in influencer outreach[14:43] - Steps to start influencer marketing campaign[16:14] - Building an affiliate army and getting organic traffic[17:38] - Addressing concerns about sending free products[19:01] - Comparing influencer marketing costs to traditional advertising[20:35] - Recap of Tomer Henn's organic approach to influencer marketing[21:19] - Information on Tomer's free resources and services<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Beyond Likes and Followers: Understanding the Influencer Landscape<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Before diving in, let's clear the air. Influencer marketing isn't just about throwing money at celebrities or social media stars with millions of followers. While reach is a factor, the most valuable influencers are those who have built trust and credibility within a specific niche. These "high-purchase intent" influencers have a loyal audience who listens to their recommendations and takes action.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Now, you might be wondering: "Isn't that what affiliates are for?" There's a subtle difference. Influencers can promote your brand organically, simply because they love your product and believe it resonates with their audience. Affiliates, on the other hand, are financially incentivized to promote your product through affiliate links.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Why Paying Upfront Might Not Be the Golden Ticket: A Case Study<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Tomer's experience highlights a crucial point: upfront payments to influencers can backfire. Take the example of a hair care product launched on Amazon in December. By leveraging a system focused on building relationships with relevant influencers, the brand secured positive mentions from 60 creators without any paid partnerships. This organic buzz resulted in a surge in sales, reaching $1,000 daily sales and securing the coveted "Best New Release" badge on Amazon within just 6-8 weeks.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This case study underscores the importance of authenticity. When influencers genuinely love your product and create content around it organically, it resonates more deeply with their audience. Paid promotions, on the other hand, can feel forced and inauthentic, potentially turning viewers away.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Breaking Free from the Algorithm: Building a Sustainable Brand<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Now, let's address the elephant in the room: why choose influencer marketing over tried-and-tested Amazon Ads (PPC)? While PPC can be effective in driving initial traffic, it comes with limitations. Here's why Tomer believes influencer marketing offers a more sustainable long-term strategy:<br />
<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>575</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>575</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Why Influencer Marketing Beats Amazon Ads Every Time</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>24:52</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14844</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to get more Money from your Most Valuable Customers</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-get-more-money-from-your-most-valuable-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-get-more-money-from-your-most-valuable-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 11:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>80/20 Your Customer List So the thing I want to talk about today is that not all customers are created equal. Just like anything else in the world, especially in the world of e-commerce or any online business environment accelerates this times two, I would say times 10, there is a power law aka 80 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/how-to-get-more-money-from-your-most-valuable-customers/">How to get more Money from your Most Valuable Customers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-get-more-money-from-your-most-valuable-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/How_to_value_a_list_of_buyers.mp3" length="5758450" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>80/20 Your Customer List So the thing I want to talk about today is that not all customers are created equal. Just like anything else in the world, especially in the world of e-commerce or any online business environment accelerates this times two,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[80/20 Your Customer List<br />
So the thing I want to talk about today is that not all customers are created equal. Just like anything else in the world, especially in the world of e-commerce or any online business environment accelerates this times two, I would say times 10, there is a power law aka 80 20.<br />
<br />
So you will find, of course, like anything else that as well as products, customers obey the same kind of rules, that the top 20 per cent of your customers probably give you 80 per cent of your profit, et cetera.<br />
Small businesses fail to create customer lists<br />
So, I've just had a bit of lunch at a local greasy spoon in North London here in Kentish Town. It's a place called Troy Cafe, just to give them a shout-out. Delicious chilli con carne on a jacket potato and coffee for under 10 pounds. Very good. Now I bet anything that those guys do not have a customer list.<br />
<br />
They're a typical small business. They're working hard. They're slightly off the beaten track. So literally just off the high street here, this is the main drag. So in E-commerce equivalent would be that they do not appear on page one for their main search terms.<br />
<br />
Here's the thing. Customer lists are incredibly powerful and valuable, but that's something everyone knows.<br />
<br />
First thing, if you're not collecting customer lists, you need to do everything in your power to do that. If you sell on Amazon, obviously they are primarily Amazon's customers and it's hard to do that. There are lots of ways of doing that. I'm not going to reiterate those now.<br />
All customers are not created equal - 80/20 customer lists<br />
Like anything else in the world, especially in the world of e-commerce or any online business environment accelerates this times two, I would say times 10, there is a power law aka 80 20. Customers follow the same kind of rules, which is to say that the top 20 per cent of your customers give you 80 per cent of your profit, and so on.<br />
How to identify your best customers from a list? <br />
Now, how do I identify the top customers in a customer list? Well, obviously how much money they spend with you is important, but there's a really old school, but really powerful formula. Very simple. But if you apply it and they do something with it, it's going to potentially transform your business.<br />
The RFM Formula<br />
It's R, F, M. R is recency, F is frequency and M is money. So the amount of money somebody spends with you is easier to track. Recency and frequency imply that you're tracking when the transactions happen and you can use various bits of software to figure this stuff out actually, I'm not going to go into the technical details.<br />
<br />
The general principle is more important because most people don't do anything about this. somebody's bought recently from you, they're much more likely to buy again, of course.<br />
Potential value vs likelihood of conversion - Money vs Recency<br />
<br />
If you want to be more refined about it, I would say the amount of money somebody spent gives you the sort of potential value as a customer, if you can persuade them to buy again.<br />
<br />
But of course, if they haven't bought from you for two years, the chance of them responding to any kind of outreach in marketing terms, whether you retarget them on Facebook all the way through to just sending them an email, is much lower. So it's less return on your effort or less probability of a conversion.<br />
Frequent customers are more valuable long-term<br />
Frequency also indicates that they might be a very valuable customer to have if they keep buying because over time the lifetime customer value probably will build.<br />
<br />
So I would say the frequency at which they buy and the money they've spent is an indication of their potential value.<br />
Recency gives conversions<br />
But recency is important. I would say rather than saying more recent custom...]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>543</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>543</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>6:00</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14674</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brompton Bikes &#8211; the power of a niche brand</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/brompton-bikes-the-power-of-a-niche-brand/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/brompton-bikes-the-power-of-a-niche-brand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 16:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hey there. It&#8217;s Michael from amazing FBA welcome to mindset moments, a little bite-sized chunks of thoughts and hopefully wisdom about business and life from my wanderings around London, and other parts of Europe. Today we are talking about the power of a niche brand: Brompton. Hello folks, I am out here with a brand [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/brompton-bikes-the-power-of-a-niche-brand/">Brompton Bikes &#8211; the power of a niche brand</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/brompton-bikes-the-power-of-a-niche-brand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Brompton_Bikes-the_power_of_a_niche_brand_V2-auphonic.mp3" length="7139159" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Hey there. It&#039;s Michael from amazing FBA welcome to mindset moments, a little bite-sized chunks of thoughts and hopefully wisdom about business and life from my wanderings around London, and other parts of Europe.</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Hey there. It's Michael from amazing FBA welcome to mindset moments, a little bite-sized chunks of thoughts and hopefully wisdom about business and life from my wanderings around London, and other parts of Europe. Today we are talking about the power of a niche brand: Brompton.<br />
<br />
Hello folks, I am out here with a brand creation story, and not mine, but I'm a customer in this case, or a would be customer. And I just wanted to reflect on, when you really, really create a fantastic product and brand combined, how strongly people will... make an effort or go out of their way to get it.<br />
<br />
And that's when you've really got a strong brand. So I'm going out of my way right now to get something. I'm walking through a strange part of town. It's freezing cold here in London, as often is. And, I need a bicycle and I live in a relatively modest sized flat in London. It's not as small as the one we used to be in, but space is always at a premium.<br />
<br />
And so I'm off shopping for the obvious solution for a cyclist in London. With space at a premium, there's one word that springs to mind, and that is Brompton.<br />
The origins of this niche brand<br />
That is a very famous brand, created in the 1970s by a Londoner. I think in response to the fact that he needed a solution to his clean needs, which is to say, a fold up bike that was good quality and actually was...<br />
<br />
Something that would fold up small and would be there for something you could take on public transport, on the tube, on the train to use what we call subway, if you're American, or the underground formally or other options like that. And which would also be a quality bike that was safe and sturdy and would cope with being folded and unfolded many, many times and would survive the process intact.<br />
<br />
Now. it's a very nice product, and that's another thing I wanted to say, like, if, if somebody hates cycling and they're going to hate Bromptons because they've never heard of them or they just think they're a complete waste of time or something, somebody who doesn't have a particular need for a bike that you can fold up and put on public transport, Or indeed into a car in a small space would find it a complete waste of time, and in many cities that would be the case. But if you're in London or for that matter somewhere like New York, I guess, I don't know if they're famous in New York, it's the obvious answer. And so the feeling is appealing to a very particular need, in this case, in quite a geographically specific situation, shall we say. I'm in London specifically, but also New York or anywhere like that, I guess would work.<br />
Having a genuinely better niche product<br />
And then the other thing, of course, is this. So, there's the person and the need, but then it's having a product that's good.<br />
<br />
my wife at one point a few years ago, bought a couple of, just on a whim. I came home and she found she'd bought two folding bikes because she sensed the need for it.<br />
<br />
Now, first of all, she never cycles having had an nasty accident here years ago, and London's pretty scary. She cyclist, I could see why she doesn't, but kind of odd that she bought two. And then I remember, that's what my wife does, . She bargain hunts and she buys more than one. Okay, now a lot of people shot that way online.<br />
<br />
That's not the sort of brand I'm talking about because when I used it, it felt, so insecure and it was so inconsistent in the way it behaved that I just felt I didn't trust it, I thought it would kill me. And by the way, that might well have been true. So I didn't use it at all. and we've given one of them away for free, despite the fact it was a hundred and fifty pounds or each or something.<br />
<br />
A hundred and twenty pounds, a hundred and fifty bucks, whatever, or euros. So, that was a kind of false economy for me, and I'm now considering buying a Brompton,]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>469</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>469</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>7:26</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14277</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Product Development Hacks in e-commerce with Jake Rosenberg of Krete</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/product-development-hacks-in-e-commerce/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/product-development-hacks-in-e-commerce/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 07:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=13981</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As an e-commerce brand owner, you know that product development is crucial to the success of your business. However, developing a new product from scratch can be a daunting task. In this article, we will discuss some product development hacks that can help you scale your e-commerce brand with minimal capital. Timestamps 0:00:00 &#124; &#8220;Developing [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/product-development-hacks-in-e-commerce/">Product Development Hacks in e-commerce with Jake Rosenberg of Krete</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/product-development-hacks-in-e-commerce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/442_Product_development_Hacks_in_e-commerce-auphonic.mp3" length="42083055" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>As an e-commerce brand owner, you know that product development is crucial to the success of your business. However, developing a new product from scratch can be a daunting task. In this article, we will discuss some product development hacks that can ...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[As an e-commerce brand owner, you know that product development is crucial to the success of your business. However, developing a new product from scratch can be a daunting task. In this article, we will discuss some product development hacks that can help you scale your e-commerce brand with minimal capital.<br />
<br />
<br />
Timestamps<br />
0:00:00 | "Developing a Skin Care Brand: A Step-by-Step Guide"<br />
0:02:51 | Exploring Options for Developing a Skincare Product<br />
0:04:16 | Exploring the Radical Path of Formulating Skincare Products at Home<br />
0:08:13 | Exploring Radical Business Practices in the Skin Care Industry<br />
0:13:08 | "Exploring the Benefits of Building a Brand vs. Private Labeling on Amazon"<br />
0:14:15 | Exploring the Benefits of Having a Complimentary Team for Product Development<br />
0:15:46 | Heading: Understanding the Basics of Website Design and Influencer Marketing for Entrepreneurs<br />
0:17:21 | Conversation on Understanding Products and Hiring the Right People<br />
0:19:04 | "Understanding the Necessity of Outsourcing and In-House Specialists for Business Success"<br />
0:21:09 | Conversation Summary: Balancing CEO and COO Roles in a Small Business<br />
0:26:28 | Conversation on Setting Clear Expectations for Employees and Establishing Long-Term Relationships<br />
0:28:39 | Conversation on Product Development: Process, Results, and Time Management<br />
0:30:12 | Exploring Strategies for Faster, Better, and Cheaper Product Development<br />
0:31:36 | "Exploring the Benefits of Researching Competitors' Products and Services"<br />
0:33:22 | Exploring the Mindset of Product Analysis and Customer Experience<br />
0:36:13 | Exploring the Benefits of Meticulous Research: A Conversation with [Name]<br />
0:37:50 | "The Benefits of Thorough Product Testing: A Conversation with [Name]"<br />
0:39:25 | Interview with Jake from Crete Brand: A Passionate Entrepreneur's Journey to Success<br />
0:41:26 | Conversation on Crete Club and Business Advice<br />
0:42:15 | Interview with Jake Rosenberg of Crete Club: Achieving Success Through Hard Work and Thoroughness<br />
<br />
Finding Your Niche/Brand<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The first step in product development is finding your niche/brand. Your brand should be something that resonates with you personally and solves a problem. Jake, the founder of Scare, had a mark on his nose from a skiing accident and was using whatever shampoo smelled nice. He realized that there was a gap in the market for men’s skincare products that were easy to use and efficient. This led to the creation of Scare, a skincare brand for men that only takes 30 seconds to use.<br />
Appealing to a Specific Set of Values and Behaviors<br />
It is essential to have a specific set of values and behaviors that you appeal to when developing your brand. Scare is centered around the idea of efficiency and saving time. Most men don’t want to spend 30 minutes in the bathroom, while some women actively enjoy the experience. Scare’s 30-second skincare routine appeals to men who want an easy and efficient solution to their skincare needs.<br />
Fast Wins<br />
Every product that you develop should give your customers a fast win. Scare’s products are designed to give customers a positive experience in the first minute of use. This is important because people are more likely to continue using a product if they see results quickly. A gym membership, for example, can be challenging to stick to because people don’t see results immediately. Scare’s products give customers a fast win, which keeps them coming back.<br />
Value Equation<br />
The value equation is a critical component of product development. The value equation is the dream outcome multiplied by the perceived likelihood of achievement divided by the time delay and effort and sacrifice.]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>442</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>442</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Product Development Hacks in e-commerce with Jake Rosenberg of Krete</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>43:50</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">13981</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding an eCommerce Niche/Brand with Jake Rosenberg of Krete</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/finding-an-commerce-niche-brand/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/finding-an-commerce-niche-brand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 07:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=13980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the world of e-commerce, finding a niche and building a strong brand is crucial to success. One way to do this is by identifying a gap in the market and creating a product that fills that gap. For Jake, the founder of a successful unisex skincare brand, this meant creating a product that was [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/finding-an-commerce-niche-brand/">Finding an eCommerce Niche/Brand with Jake Rosenberg of Krete</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/finding-an-commerce-niche-brand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/440_Audio_Finding_An_eCommerce_Niche_Brand-auphonic.mp3" length="20540185" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>In the world of e-commerce, finding a niche and building a strong brand is crucial to success. One way to do this is by identifying a gap in the market and creating a product that fills that gap. For Jake, the founder of a successful unisex skincare br...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
In the world of e-commerce, finding a niche and building a strong brand is crucial to success. One way to do this is by identifying a gap in the market and creating a product that fills that gap. For Jake, the founder of a successful unisex skincare brand, this meant creating a product that was efficient, fast, and appealing to a broader range of men and women. In this article, we will explore how Jake identified a niche, created a unisex skincare brand, and used fast wins and efficiency to build a valuable e-commerce brand.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Timestamps<br />
0:00:00 | Interview with Jake Rosenberg, Founder and CEO of Crete Skincare Company<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
0:02:23 | Conversation on Skincare Company and Market Response<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
0:04:00 | Exploring the Shift from Male-Focused Skincare to Unisex with Crete Founder, David Lim<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
0:07:36 | Exploring Masculine and Feminine Niches for Customer Experience Vibes<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
0:09:02 | Exploring the Value Proposition of 1 Minute Skincare<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
0:11:52 | Discussion on Aspirational Outcomes and Fast Wins in Product Development<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
0:13:41 | Exploring the Psychology of Product Use: How to Create a Positive User Experience<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
0:17:48 | The Benefits of Delivering Fast Wins for Business Success<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
0:19:24 | Product Development: The Key to Capturing and Sustaining Attention in the Age of Attention<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Identifying a Niche: Creating a Unisex Skincare Brand<br />
Jake's brand was born out of his own need for a skincare solution that was both effective and efficient. After suffering a skiing accident that left a mark on his nose, Jake realized the importance of skincare but found that the existing options on the market were either too time-consuming or too gendered. He wanted to create a skincare solution that would <a href="https://amazingfba.com/192-amazon-appeal-letter-joshua-price/">appeal</a> to a broader range of men and women and would take no more than 30 seconds in the bathroom.<br />
Efficiency: The Key to a Successful E-commerce Brand<br />
Jake knew that the most precious resource for his target audience was time. To create a successful <a href="https://amazingfba.com/when-your-customer-wants-to-return-a-product-how-to-protect-your-e-commerce-brand/">e-commerce brand</a>, he had to design a product that was efficient and easy to use. This meant creating a product that would provide fast wins – positive experiences in the first minute of use – and consistently deliver results.<br />
Fast Wins: Building Credibility and Creating Value for Your Brand<br />
Fast wins are crucial to building credibility and creating value for your brand. For Jake's brand, this meant creating a product that would give users positive experiences in the first minute of use. This approach helped his brand stand out from the competition and gave users the confidence to continue using his products. The <a href="https://amazingfba.com/amazon-business-values-maximise-your-fba-business-value/">value proposition</a> of his brand was clear – it was a unisex skincare solution that was fast, efficient, and consistently delivered results.<br />
Conclusion<br />
Finding a niche and building a strong brand in e-commerce requires a deep understanding of your target audience and their needs. For Jake, this meant identifying a gap in the market and creating a product that was efficient, fast, and appealing to a broader range of men and women. By focusing on fast wins and consistently delivering results, Jake was able to build a credible and valuable brand that has achie...]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>440</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>440</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Finding an eCommerce Niche/Brand with Jake Rosenberg of Krete</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>21:24</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">13980</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Export to Germany for UK Sellers with Jacob McQuoid of Avask</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-export-to-germany-for-uk-sellers-with-jacob-mcquoid-of-avask/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-export-to-germany-for-uk-sellers-with-jacob-mcquoid-of-avask/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 07:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=13486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Germany is still Amazon&#8217;s second biggest marketplace by value in the world, beating the UK and Japan. It&#8217;s a great opportunity for many sellers to sell there. However&#8230; UK, American, Australian Amazon Sellers &#8211; or any other non-European sellers &#8211; struggle to export to the EU. Whether it&#8217;s VAT, customs or other red tape, it&#8217;s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/how-to-export-to-germany-for-uk-sellers-with-jacob-mcquoid-of-avask/">How to Export to Germany for UK Sellers with Jacob McQuoid of Avask</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-export-to-germany-for-uk-sellers-with-jacob-mcquoid-of-avask/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/02_How_to_Export_to_Germany_for_UK_Sellers_with_Jacob_McQuoid_of_Avask-auphonic.mp3" length="19093210" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Germany is still Amazon&#039;s second biggest marketplace by value in the world, beating the UK and Japan. It&#039;s a great opportunity for many sellers to sell there. - However... - UK, American, Australian Amazon Sellers - or any other non-European sellers ...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Germany is still Amazon's second biggest marketplace by value in the world, beating the UK and Japan. It's a great opportunity for many sellers to sell there.<br />
<br />
However...<br />
<br />
UK, American, Australian Amazon Sellers - or any other non-European sellers - struggle to export to the EU. Whether it's VAT, customs or other red tape, it's often confusing and frustrating.  <br />
<br />
For UK sellers, Brexit has been a brutal experience. From being able to sell effortlessly, we’ve had to learn to jump through ever-changing hoops. <br />
<br />
Step forward Avask. Used by several 10K Collective mastermind members, they are tried and trusted experts in solving these problems - and getting us access to those lucrative European markets! <br />
<br />
What You'll Learn<br />
<br />
 	* Understanding the shipping polices in Germany<br />
 	* The cause and effects of engaging with German customs<br />
 	* The Alternatives : UK to Netherlands<br />
 	* Discover the EPRs for UK-Based People<br />
 	* Other things other than VAT and indirect rep do we need in place<br />
<br />
Get In Touch <br />
<br />
 	* <a href="https://www.avaskgroup.com/?afmc=7t" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Find Out More About Avask</a><br />
 	* <a href="https://www.avaskgroup.com/?afmc=7t" target="_blank" rel="noopener">More info about exports</a><br />
 	* <a href="http://amazingfba.com/Jacob">Book A Call with Jacob</a><br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>356</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>356</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>How to Export to Germany for UK Sellers with Jacob McQuoid of Avask</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>19:53</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">13486</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Sell on Amazon Europe with Andy Hooper</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-sell-on-amazon-europe-with-andy-hooper/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-sell-on-amazon-europe-with-andy-hooper/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 07:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon europe countries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon european marketplaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon sales in europe by country]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon seller europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sell on amazon europe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=13456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Selling in Europe has been a goal for many Amazon sellers. Whether you&#8217;re based in UK or USA it&#8217;s always a siren call. But is it worth the hassle? Many of my big seller friends in the UK made millions of pounds and Euros before Brexit. Same is true for the 7-figure clients in my [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/how-to-sell-on-amazon-europe-with-andy-hooper/">How to Sell on Amazon Europe with Andy Hooper</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-sell-on-amazon-europe-with-andy-hooper/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Part_01-MV_and_Part_01-AH-auphonic.mp3" length="22718170" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Selling in Europe has been a goal for many Amazon sellers. - Whether you&#039;re based in UK or USA it&#039;s always a siren call. But is it worth the hassle? - Many of my big seller friends in the UK made millions of pounds and Euros before Brexit.</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Selling in Europe has been a goal for many Amazon sellers.<br />
<br />
Whether you're based in UK or USA it's always a siren call. But is it worth the hassle?<br />
<br />
Many of my big seller friends in the UK made millions of pounds and Euros before Brexit. Same is true for the 7-figure clients in my mastermind.<br />
<br />
But about post Brexit? Is it still viable?<br />
<br />
There seem to be so many issues. Between VAT registration, "indirect representatives", and customs declarations, it can seem very intimidating. Add in the vagaries of the German government and it can feel like it's not worthwhile.<br />
<br />
If that's how you feel, it's worth thinking again. For starters, Amazon Germany and Amazon UK together account for well over 2/3 of all European Amazon sales. And with German sales being even bigger than UK ones, they are problems worth solving. Particularly as you're not the only seller facing these problems. And on the other side of barriers to entry are: less competitive markets!<br />
<br />
We talk to the specialist in solving these issues, Andy Hooper of Global Ecommerce Experts.<br />
<br />
&nbsp;<br />
<br />
What You'll Learn<br />
<br />
 	* The opportunities of selling Amazon in Europe<br />
 	* The benefits of expanding your market to Europe<br />
 	* The main reason why people are scared in selling in Europe<br />
 	* Understand VAT Compliance and get yourself ahead with your competition<br />
 	* Finding the common red tape issues<br />
 	* The benefits of being an entrepreneur instead of a shipping agent<br />
 	* The pains of shipping in some areas in Europe<br />
<br />
Resources<br />
<br />
 	* Get in touch with <a href="http://amazingfba.com/global" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Global Ecommerce Experts</a><br />
 	* Connect with <a href="http://amazingfba.com/andyhooper" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andy Hooper</a><br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>349</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>349</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>How to Sell on Amazon Europe with Andy Hooper</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>23:40</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">13456</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best Ecommerce SEO  - Free Traffic to Your e-Commerce Site with On-Page SEO for DTC with Farzad Rashidi</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/best-ecommerce-seo-free-traffic-to-your-e-commerce-site-with-on-page-seo-for-dtc-with-farzad-rashidi/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/best-ecommerce-seo-free-traffic-to-your-e-commerce-site-with-on-page-seo-for-dtc-with-farzad-rashidi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 07:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scaling An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=12858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Amazon sellers obsess about how to get their own ecommerce site. There are excellent reasons why you’d want your own DTC (direct to consumer site) Amazon IS a nightmare at times. With Amazon Account Suspension, listing suspension and intellectual property violations all significant risks, it’s a wise move for risk diversification. And with Amazon ads [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/best-ecommerce-seo-free-traffic-to-your-e-commerce-site-with-on-page-seo-for-dtc-with-farzad-rashidi/">Best Ecommerce SEO  &#8211; Free Traffic to Your e-Commerce Site with On-Page SEO for DTC with Farzad Rashidi</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/best-ecommerce-seo-free-traffic-to-your-e-commerce-site-with-on-page-seo-for-dtc-with-farzad-rashidi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/01_Best_Ecommerce_SEO-Free_Traffic_to_Your_e-Commerce_Site_with_on-page_SEO_for_DTC-auphonic.mp3" length="32427780" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Amazon sellers obsess about how to get their own ecommerce site. There are excellent reasons why you’d want your own DTC (direct to consumer site) Amazon IS a nightmare at times. With Amazon Account Suspension,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Amazon sellers obsess about how to get their own ecommerce site. There are excellent reasons why you’d want your own DTC (direct to consumer site)<br />
Amazon IS a nightmare at times. With Amazon Account Suspension, listing suspension and intellectual property violations all significant risks, it’s a wise move for risk diversification. And with Amazon ads costs going up all the time, it seems like it might even make financial sense.<br />
<br />
However. once you're off Amazon you're confronted with another challenge: How on earth do I get quality traffic to my site? And how do I get enough of it to make a real business? So many Amazon sellers have a Shopify or woocommerce site that does almost nothing. Others pay so much for traffic in paid ads that they can't make a profit.<br />
<br />
Most serious DTC owners know that SEO has to be the backbone of traffic. But how do we actually go about SEO in a way that works? Today we talk with Farzad Rashidi of Respona on exactly how to get that precious Google organic traffic in a way that’s doable for busy entrepreneurs.<br />
What You’ll Learn<br />
<br />
 	* Find out what's the buzz all about with Respona<br />
 	* The backstory of Farzad and how marketing paved way with Respona<br />
 	* The value of Paid Ads<br />
 	* Understanding the ins and out of Cold Out Reach<br />
 	* Maximizing value with Cold Outreach<br />
<br />
Freebies<br />
<br />
 	* Get your free "Recipe Book" for Outreach Traffic Tactics <a href="http://www.amazingfba.com/backlink">here</a>!<br />
 	* Your free demo with Farzad himself at <a href="https://respona.com">https://respona.com</a><br />
<br />
&nbsp;]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>332</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>332</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Best Ecommerce SEO  - Free Traffic to Your e-Commerce Site with On-Page SEO for DTC with Farzad Rashidi</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>33:47</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">12858</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
