<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0"

	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Custom Product Design - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
	<atom:link href="https://amazingfba.com/category/custom-product-design/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/custom-product-design/</link>
	<description>Amazon Coach &#38; Mastermind Convenor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:54:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Amazing-FBA-new-logo-no-white-background-1-e1656858629506.png?fit=150%2C150&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Custom Product Design - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
	<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/custom-product-design/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<atom:link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
	<itunes:summary>Do you sell private label or custom products on Amazon UK, USA or Europe? Or are you gearing up to do it? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you are struggling to grow sales, seeing profits erode and feel a long way from a sellable valuable business, we can help. If you&#039;re already killing it, why not grow faster and make even more cash? &lt;br /&gt;
Either way, you&#039;re in the right place. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our experts answer these questions and more - experts like Greg Mercer of Jungle Scout, Will Tjernlund, Manuel Becvar, Chris Green, Kevin King, and many many more. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whether you are trying to get Amazon product research right; help sourcing from China; optimizing Amazon listings; dealing with  Amazon PPC (aka Amazon ads) - we&#039;ve got you covered!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you&#039;re UK based and you want to sell in UK or USA; and if you&#039;re US based and you&#039;re curious about - or selling in - UK or Europe, you can&#039;t afford to miss the detailed insights you&#039;ll get.</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
	<itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>Michael Veazey</itunes:name>
	</itunes:owner>
	<copyright>&#xA9;Michael Veazey 2015-2022</copyright>
	<podcast:license>&#xA9;Michael Veazey 2015-2022</podcast:license>
	<podcast:medium>podcast</podcast:medium>
	<itunes:subtitle>Amazing FBA Amazon and ECommerce Podcast, for Amazon Private Label Sellers, Shopify, Magento or Woocommerce business owners, and other e-commerce sellers and digital entrepreneurs.</itunes:subtitle>
	<image>
		<title>Custom Product Design - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
		<url>https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg</url>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/custom-product-design/</link>
	</image>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Careers" />
	</itunes:category>
	<googleplay:category text="Business"/>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Marketing" />
	</itunes:category>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Entrepreneurship" />
	</itunes:category>
	<rawvoice:rating>TV-G</rawvoice:rating>
	<rawvoice:location>London, England</rawvoice:location>
	<podcast:location>London, England</podcast:location>
	<podcast:podping usesPodping="true" />
	<rawvoice:subscribe feed="https://amazingfba.com/category/custom-product-design/feed/" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/ug/podcast/amazing-fba/id1030237683" spotify="https://open.spotify.com/show/32Cryk51sxVlF03B38UeoJ" amazon_music="https://music.amazon.co.uk/podcasts/3237ef11-0180-45a2-adff-2b4ab89267b5/amazing-fba-amazon-and-ecommerce-podcast-for-amazon-private-label-sellers-shopify-magento-or-woocommerce-business-owners-and-other-e-commerce-sellers-and-digital-entrepreneurs"></rawvoice:subscribe>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">203239326</site>	<item>
		<title>Is your product difficult and dangerous? Mike&#8217;s loft ladder!</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/is-your-product-difficult-and-dangerous-mikes-loft-ladder/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/is-your-product-difficult-and-dangerous-mikes-loft-ladder/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Custom Product Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes consumer products aren&#8217;t just confusing or overly complex. Sometimes they can be downright difficult to use. They can even be dangerous. They might even be deadly. Such is Mike&#8217;s loft ladder. Difficult, frustrating and downright dangerous, this is an example of consumer product design sins to avoid at all costs. If you design products [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/is-your-product-difficult-and-dangerous-mikes-loft-ladder/">Is your product difficult and dangerous? Mike&#8217;s loft ladder!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/is-your-product-difficult-and-dangerous-mikes-loft-ladder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Is_your_product_difficult_and_dangerous_auphonic.mp3" length="4652100" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Sometimes consumer products aren&#039;t just confusing or overly complex. Sometimes they can be downright difficult to use. They can even be dangerous. They might even be deadly. Such is Mike&#039;s loft ladder. Difficult, frustrating and downright dangerous,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Sometimes consumer products aren't just confusing or overly complex. Sometimes they can be downright difficult to use. They can even be dangerous. They might even be deadly. Such is Mike's loft ladder. Difficult, frustrating and downright dangerous, this is an example of consumer product design sins to avoid at all costs. <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
If you design products - or have them designed for you, you MUST think about this. Even if you're "just" ultimately liable if someone hurts themselves,  you've got to be so careful not to produce products that harm your users. <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Otherwise, it's just a matter of time before someone hurts themselves using your product. Or you're just hoping for good luck.  And luck, as the Marines say, is not a strategy.  <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>5:32</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">15002</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is your product confusing consumers?</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/is-your-product-confusing-consumers/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/is-your-product-confusing-consumers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 14:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Custom Product Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Is your product confusing consumers? Is your product confusing consumers? Hey folks today you find me in the glamorous location of our garage and I&#8217;ve got a simple but really important point to make about consumer product design, particularly if you&#8217;ve got a complicated product. So here is our trusty tumble dryer. I wish it [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/is-your-product-confusing-consumers/">Is your product confusing consumers?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/is-your-product-confusing-consumers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Is_your_product_confusing_consumers_.mp3" length="6332612" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Is your product confusing consumers?    Is your product confusing consumers?    Hey folks today you find me in the glamorous location of our garage and I&#039;ve got a simple but really important point to make about consumer product design,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Is your product confusing consumers?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Is your product confusing consumers?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Hey folks today you find me in the glamorous location of our garage and I've got a simple but really important point to make about consumer product design, particularly if you've got a complicated product.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
So here is our trusty tumble dryer.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
I wish it were a washer dryer, but for various reasons, my wife wants to keep the old washing machine, so we end up schlepping stuff from one place to another.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
So by the way, hint number one, if you can create a machine that solves two problems in one go, and they logically belong very, very closely together, like washing clothes, what do you always do?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
You dry them.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
If such a thing doesn't exist in your market, or it's not very functional, that's a good hint.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
But that's not the main thing for today. The main thing for today is this look at this panel.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
We've got a bunch of different options, look how many options, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14 different options.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Guess which one I always use? Eco. Why? Because I want it simple. I've got four options for how dry I want it. The one is hanger dry and the previous one is like, extra dry. And then the other one is iron it.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
I would argue that you probably need three settings maximum there. Then you've got everything else.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Timing, how long it lasts for I don't even know what that does.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
That's the temperature obviously, that's something special. Guess what I do? I use Eco, I choose the driest one, I press on and then I'm done.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
if you overcomplicate the user interface of any product at all, you are probably not adding value for anyone.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
And you probably think you are adding value because engineers love complexity and they love solving problems. And so the product designers, as you get very, very deep into a product there, you realize there are more and more nuances. And you think you're adding value by adding complication. I very much doubt you are.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
I think that you're very likely to be adding stress to a consumer's life.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
What they want is something that works reliably, is very, very, very simple to use and gets them the outcome they want.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Now, okay, there may be a few different outcomes and I'm not saying you shouldn't have a few different options.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
But the reality is that your consumer is going to choose one of two of them.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
There's a good argument in favor of creating something very simple.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Years ago, Anita Broderick, I think. The creator of the incredibly successful brand, the body shop said and this was back in the nineties or the two thousands, right?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
When home computers were relatively new thing.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
" I think somebody should can invent the computer, which has four buttons on and off, and that come on with the other three where, and she makes a valid point.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Most computer systems, most domestic appliances. are way more complicated than you need, right?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
I could take you indoors and look at the oven. But let's look at this.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This is actually not too bad as interfaces go, but guess what? When my father in law turned up here, He's got an oven, an electric oven like this one. He put this on in order to put the oven on, but guess what that tiny symbol means? Grill. Well, first of all, if you're selling products to the UK, why don't you put English on them?<br />
<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>593</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>593</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>6:36</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14999</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brand Identity Definition - eCommerce Brand Strategy</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/brand-identity-definition/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/brand-identity-definition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 07:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Custom Product Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=13782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brand Identity Definition If you&#8217;re selling your products on a website, it&#8217;s important to give your brand an identity. The best way to do this is with a brand strategy. A brand strategy can help you understand what makes your product different and how to communicate that to customers. It also helps you decide when [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/brand-identity-definition/">Brand Identity Definition &#8211; eCommerce Brand Strategy</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/brand-identity-definition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/394_Brand_Identity_Definition-eCommerce_Brand_Strategy_JB-auphonic.mp3" length="32215457" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Brand Identity Definition If you&#039;re selling your products on a website, it&#039;s important to give your brand an identity. The best way to do this is with a brand strategy. A brand strategy can help you understand what makes your product different and how...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Brand Identity Definition<br />
If you're selling your products on a website, it's important to give your brand an identity. The best way to do this is with a brand strategy. A brand strategy can help you understand what makes your product different and how to communicate that to customers. It also helps you decide when it's time for a rebranding project! What is a brand identity definition? A brand identity is everything your customers associate with your products and company. A brand strategy is a plan that helps you decide how to communicate your brand. This includes things like what your logo will look like, what colors you'll use and how you're going to talk about yourself. It's all about understanding who your customers are, what they need from your product, and how you can meet those needs better than anyone else!<br />
<br />
Timestamps for Podcast<br />
[00:35:02] Intro: Curated Marketplace For Custom Design<br />
[01:41:77] What is Brand Identity?<br />
[03:37:07] <a href="http://www.Amazingfba.com/crowdspring">Crowdspring</a> Offers A Wide Variety of Designer Types<br />
[06:49:41] Brand Perception is Guided By The Companies<br />
[09:37:82] The Product Has To Be Good But So Does The Whole Experience<br />
[12:07:36] What Are The Steps In Creating A Brand Identity From The Beginning?<br />
[12:38:30] The Core Brand : Visual Identity<br />
[14:03:35] Transferring Your Design Into Packaging<br />
[16:37:32] Brand Consistency<br />
[18:13:38] How Do We Get Consistency?<br />
[20:53:53] How Do We Create Brand Guidelines? Is it Necessary to Hire Someone?<br />
[23:03:76] Branding and Packaging<br />
[27:22:64] <a href="http://www.Amazingfba.com/crowdspring">Crowdspring</a> and their Services<br />
<a href="http://www.Amazingfba.com/crowdspring">About our Guests- Jason Byer and Crowd Spring</a><br />
Are the  99 Designs of e-commerce with two tweaks. Firstly, they have a very highly selected set of designers.  Secondly, their designers  include  industrial designers (aka product designers).<br />
<br />
 	* Get Your <a href="http://www.amazingfba.com/BrandGrade">Free Custom Brand Report Here</a> !<br />
 	* Get a $35 Off Your First Product Here : <a href="http://www.Amazingfba.com/crowdspring">Get It Here</a> ! <br />
<br />
What Does a Successful Brand Identity Look Like?<br />
If you want to build a successful brand identity, you need to start with the basics. Brand identity is the sum of all the elements that make up your brand. This includes not only what you say about your business and how it’s doing, but also how others perceive these things by looking at your logo and website, reading some of your content on social media, or watching videos on YouTube.<br />
<br />
A successful brand identity is one where all these components work together as part of an overall strategy that helps customers understand what makes this company different from others in its market niche. It does this through:<br />
<br />
 	A well-defined promise or value proposition;<br />
 	Clear messaging (whether verbal or visual);<br />
 	Consistent branding across platforms; and<br />
 	Appropriate use of colours, fonts and imagery<br />
<br />
How to Create a Great Brand Identity for Your eCommerce Business<br />
A great brand identity is one that is recognizable and distinct. This means that it should be consistent across all channels, including your website, social media platforms, packaging and marketing campaigns.<br />
<br />
Being consistent with your brand identity will allow you to establish trust among consumers. That helps them feel comfortable making purchases from you. Your logo is the key component of this. Make sure it stands out from other logos. That way, customers can easily identify it as belonging to your company. Your logo should also be memorable so that customers don't forget about you after they've made their purchase.<br />
<br />
By using the same colors,]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>389</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>389</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title> Brand Identity Definition - eCommerce Brand Strategy</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>33:33</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">13782</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazon Product Development with Mina Elias of MMA Nutrition</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-product-development-with-mina-elias-of-mma-nutrition/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-product-development-with-mina-elias-of-mma-nutrition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 05:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Custom Product Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retail Arbitrage RA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=12058</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Custom Product Development is one of the biggest and hardest jobs in e-Commerce. Often the focus among Amazon Private Label/custom product sellers is on hacks to the selling side of your business. While those are important, if you don&#8217;t have a product that solves your customers&#8217; problems better than the competition, it&#8217;s going to be [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/amazon-product-development-with-mina-elias-of-mma-nutrition/">Amazon Product Development with Mina Elias of MMA Nutrition</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-product-development-with-mina-elias-of-mma-nutrition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Amazon_Product_Development_with_Mina_Elias_of_MMA_Nutrition-auphonic.mp3" length="36782497" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Custom Product Development is one of the biggest and hardest jobs in e-Commerce. Often the focus among Amazon Private Label/custom product sellers is on hacks to the selling side of your business. While those are important,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Custom Product Development is one of the biggest and hardest jobs in e-Commerce. Often the focus among Amazon Private Label/custom product sellers is on hacks to the selling side of your business.<br />
While those are important, if you don't have a product that solves your customers' problems better than the competition, it's going to be very hard to have even medium term success. In the end, if your customers love the results of your product, they will reward you with good reviews. In turn, this gives great conversion rates and keeps your units selling, your cash flowing and your profits growing.<br />
Mina Elias is the Chief Executive Officer at MMA Nutrition and is a living example of how customer and results obsession drives product development for raving fan customers on Amazon.<br />
Find out how Mina who was obsessed with nutrition, turned his MMA career into a successful Amazon business.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
<br />
To find out more about<a href="http://www.Trivium.group"> Mina Elias' PPC Agency click here.</a><br />
<br />
If you want to check out some<a href="https://checkpointlearning.thomsonreuters.com/"> PPC training, click here.</a><br />
<br />
&nbsp;<br />
You'll Learn:<br />
<br />
 	* To simplify your product<br />
 	* How Mina created his first supplement and how it impacted his business<br />
 	* What Mina had to create to solve his nutritional need<br />
 	* How to do product development<br />
 	* Identify a problem and try to create a product to solve that issue<br />
 	* How to research solutions<br />
 	* To look at other products and find their limitations<br />
 	* How to use your strengths to your advantage<br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>235</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>235</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Amazon Product Development with Mina Elias of MMA Nutrition</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>38:19</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">12058</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Product Packaging with Simon Shushtari of Eco Brothers</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/product-packaging-with-simon-shushtari-of-eco-brothers/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/product-packaging-with-simon-shushtari-of-eco-brothers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 05:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Custom Product Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=11320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Eco Brothers have a factory in Yunnan South China and they do custom packaging for Amazon sellers. Simon marks out the reasons why packaging matters in online business. It not only gives customers their first impression of the product but gives them an unboxing experience which excites them and makes them feel good about the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/product-packaging-with-simon-shushtari-of-eco-brothers/">Product Packaging with Simon Shushtari of Eco Brothers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/product-packaging-with-simon-shushtari-of-eco-brothers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/10K_Simon_of_Eco-Brothers-auphonic.mp3" length="39813119" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Eco Brothers have a factory in Yunnan South China and they do custom packaging for Amazon sellers. - Simon marks out the reasons why packaging matters in online business. It not only gives customers their first impression of the product but gives them...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Eco Brothers have a factory in Yunnan South China and they do custom packaging for Amazon sellers.<br />
<br />
Simon marks out the reasons why packaging matters in online business. It not only gives customers their first impression of the product but gives them an unboxing experience which excites them and makes them feel good about the product.<br />
<br />
If you want to get in touch with Eco Brothers, click<a href="https://amazingfba.com/eco"> here.</a><br />
<br />
&nbsp;<br />
<br />
For more packaging ideas, check out <a href="https://www.thepackagingpro.com/blog/packaging-knowledge-base/creative-packaging-design-ideas/">Packaging Pro.</a><br />
<br />
Learn how to make the difference your brand needs. Download the complete guide on how to choose the right materials, packaging structure, and art finishing for your brand:<br />
<br />
<a href="https://amazingfba.com/download-the-free-slide-from-eco-brothers/">Download the FREE slide here</a><br />
<br />
&nbsp;<br />
You'll Learn:<br />
<br />
 	* Why packaging matters<br />
 	* The big mistakes of packaging<br />
 	* The kinds of paper/cardboard to use for the particular products<br />
 	* That there is more demand for eco-friendly packaging <br />
 	* How to save money by working on the dimensions of your packaging<br />
 	* The best process for sourcing packaging<br />
 	* The importance of Art finish visual differentiation<br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>159</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>159</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Product Packaging with Simon Shushtari of Eco Brothers</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>41:28</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">11320</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diversifying Your Amazon Business with Rory Stern</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/diversifying-your-amazon-business/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/diversifying-your-amazon-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 05:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Custom Product Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scaling An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=8087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“We Deliver the results you hoped your last agency would” Rory F. Stern has been a best-kept secret working behind the scenes to help build, grow, and scale many successful online companies for the last 14 years.  Today, he manages a small boutique media buying team that specializes in multi-channel traffic.  He is best known [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/diversifying-your-amazon-business/">Diversifying Your Amazon Business with Rory Stern</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/diversifying-your-amazon-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/395_DIversifying_your_eCommerce_business_with_Rory_Stern-25_03_2020_21_58-Auphonic.mp3" length="43751130" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>“We Deliver the results you hoped your last agency would” Rory F. Stern has been a best-kept secret working behind the scenes to help build, grow, and scale many successful online companies for the last 14 years.  Today,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[“We Deliver the results you hoped your last agency would”<br />
Rory F. Stern has been a best-kept secret working behind the scenes to help build, grow, and scale many successful online companies for the last 14 years.  Today, he manages a small boutique media buying team that specializes in multi-channel traffic.  He is best known for creating ads that convert and being able to get a lot of policy challenged offers approved and running on Facebook.<br />
Core business is growing a business with paid traffic.<br />
That includes FaceBook, Instagram, google search, google display, Youtube, Google Shopping<br />
<br />
<br />
 	Ecomm, supplements, info product<br />
 	Specialise in compliance and policy<br />
<br />
Ten years ago, traffic was this “black box” - only a handful of people knew what they were doing.<br />
You can ‘control” the flow of traffic - so you can predictably scale your business.<br />
Whereas scaling based on organic traffic and partnerships can be under less control.<br />
<br />
What are the different experiences of your clients?<br />
Not done a lot of work for solely FBA businesses.<br />
Typically a brand that is on Amazon comes to them to control more of the customer journey.<br />
Anybody who happens to watch this in the future - there is a very unique challenge in our world. But that is going to be what any business faces in any recession.<br />
Rory tries to build a business from a strong foundation, they are a 3-legged stool<br />
Right now, the majority of his clients are seeing “normal” volatility.<br />
In the USA, they are just breaking into things that are really bad.<br />
Lost client last night from Australia - do live events.<br />
“We need to focus on getting you online”!<br />
What they offer physically is able to go online.<br />
Some clients are thriving -from 2X ROAS to 6x ROAS<br />
They happened to be in the right place.<br />
Other agencies have lost ⅓ of clients!<br />
Amazon businesses typically have traffic within the Amazon eco-system.<br />
So you don’t have a lot of ROAS.<br />
<br />
What are the characteristics of the physical goods businesses that are weathering the storm?<br />
Importing from China did lead to shut down for a while.<br />
Now there is the issue with FBA side - Amazon has shut off inbound shipping.<br />
Several distribution centres in the USA have had Covid19 cases confirmed.<br />
Is there anything you can do?<br />
One client with 6X ROAS is a physical product company, based out of Western USA, only essential employees can report; they are selling the right kind of product.<br />
<br />
In light of what’s going on right now - how do you diversify?<br />
How do you pivot into digital products?<br />
There are multiple steps to this.<br />
<br />
Risks of Amazon businesses<br />
The main issue is Amazon owns the customer!<br />
What happens when I can’t rely on Amazon?<br />
<br />
<br />
 	They label your own product<br />
 	They kick you off amazon etc.<br />
<br />
How do I get control of my customers?<br />
Getting people on email list is really hard.<br />
Your inserts are limited.<br />
<br />
So how do I develop my own Customer list?<br />
Start to build an audience via some moderate-budget paid ads.<br />
Then choose an Email platform and build a list eg aWeber, ActiveCampaign,<br />
<br />
How do we start doing lead generation? - building a list? <br />
So that when supply chains open up, we are outside Amazon and Alibaba<br />
How do you get ready?<br />
With ecomm brands, they like to do contests.<br />
Built an essential oil accessory business on back of contests<br />
<br />
<br />
 	FaceBook ads<br />
 	Opt in to email lists<br />
 	Ran Kickstarter campaigns for product development.<br />
<br />
 	They can take 30-60 days<br />
<br />
<br />
 	If you’ve listed a pillow on Amazon, there’s a decent chance you have someone in the family with sleep issues<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:episode>395</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>395</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>45:34</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">8087</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sourcing Models for Amazon with Robyn Johnson</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/sourcing-models-for-amazon/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/sourcing-models-for-amazon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 05:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Wholesale FBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Custom Product Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Arbitrage OA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Retail Arbitrage RA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starting An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=8028</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Robyn Johnson will be talking about the essentials and best practices for sourcing models. Background Robyn was not at all capitalist. She was a youth pastor &#8211; but “the benefits are out of this world” when working for the church. They had to test their son for diseases &#8211; her 1st thought was: “How do [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/sourcing-models-for-amazon/">Sourcing Models for Amazon with Robyn Johnson</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/sourcing-models-for-amazon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/2020_02_18-robyn-johnson-1-final.mp3" length="33427419" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Robyn Johnson will be talking about the essentials and best practices for sourcing models. Background Robyn was not at all capitalist. She was a youth pastor - but “the benefits are out of this world” when working for the church.</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Robyn Johnson will be talking about the essentials and best practices for sourcing models.<br />
<br />
<br />
Background<br />
Robyn was not at all capitalist. She was a youth pastor - but “the benefits are out of this world” when working for the church. They had to test their son for diseases - her 1st thought was: “How do I keep my kid alive and not lose my house?”<br />
<br />
Robyn did the <a href="https://www.daveramsey.com/dave-ramsey-7-baby-steps">Dave Ramsey plan</a>. She went from Craigslist to eBay to Amazon, built $100 into a $1 Million business and became a sourcing models specialist. <br />
4 mainstream sourcing models for Resellers on Amazon<br />
<br />
 	Used Books, <br />
 	RA or OA, <br />
 	Wholesale<br />
 	Brand Management <br />
<br />
Used Books <br />
Quite a few people do multi-millions on this. <br />
<br />
The margins are great but it’s dirty physical work. <br />
<br />
If you have $100, $50K or $1M, you can start with used books; stay away from textbooks!<br />
<br />
They are a great way to learn the platform because you eliminate a lot of the learning curve. <br />
RA/Retail Arbitrage <br />
If you can’t do used books, this is the next easiest. <br />
<br />
You just go to a location - you need to be a treasure hunter.<br />
<br />
Either in person (RA)<br />
<br />
Or OA - Online Arbitrage. <br />
<br />
There can be IP and scalability issues. <br />
<br />
There are a couple of people doing this at scale but it’s challenging. <br />
<br />
Scaling OA past $250K mark will mean you have to create some new infrastructure. <br />
Wholesale ($1,000-$3,000 capital needed)<br />
This is often how people move into the next stage. <br />
<br />
It’s very delayed gratification- a lot of energy goes in and you’re not able to really check. <br />
<br />
You have to put a lot of leads in, and you have a lot of back and forth with brand owners. <br />
<br />
It takes 60-90 days to get approved for a brand. <br />
<br />
It will then take 3-6 weeks to get your first inventory into Amazon. <br />
<br />
You need to be analytical, happy with spreadsheets. You need someone steady and consistent. <br />
<br />
There’s no big roulette risk like PL. <br />
<br />
Robyn gets 60%+ margins on all her wholesale. But she goes through stacks of data! For example, she had a 7-foot high stack of brochures from suppliers from her last trade show visit.  <br />
Private Label $5K-20K <br />
Robyn has family from China - but doesn’t PL! This is high risk - so Robyn doesn’t want the risk. You have risks around IP or liability. But above all, you need to bring some value to the marketplace. <br />
<br />
Wholesale is blackjack, where PL is roulette. So you have to have to think about your risk tolerance. <br />
Brand management<br />
Usually, you’d need to start with value-added wholesale and get experience and case studies before transitioning over to this. <br />
How do you match the entrepreneur and the sourcing models?<br />
<br />
 	Cashflow<br />
 	Experience in job<br />
 	What’s working so far<br />
 	Physical abilities<br />
<br />
If someone is very analytical, they might be good at wholesale. Whereas for Brand management - you’ll have technical skills and people skills. <br />
Personality and Amazon sourcing models<br />
If someone’s very spontaneous and is willing to work very hard, they do well in RA and OA. <br />
<br />
For RA to scale up, you’ll need to talk to managers. <br />
<br />
OA people are probably more introverted and very analytical and data-centered. <br />
<br />
Wholesale works for people who push well through numbers. It helps to be extroverted at trade shows. <br />
<br />
Brand management is better for those who have done $250-500K on Amazon and have at least some case studies. <br />
Private Label<br />
For private label, you need super high-risk tolerance. <br />
<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:episode>392</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>392</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>42:55</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">8028</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Protecting The Product Design with Ryan Shaffett of XQ Manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/protecting-the-product-design-with-ryan-shaffett-of-xq-manufacturing/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/protecting-the-product-design-with-ryan-shaffett-of-xq-manufacturing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 05:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Custom Product Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?post_type=10k&#038;p=6568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Protecting The Product Design The role of Patents in protecting your product design Protecting your Product Design doesn&#8217;t necessarily start with  patent protections. One key is to minimise the chance of your supplier selling your product to other retailers.  Ryan&#8217;s team works hard on the selection of and relationship with suppliers to ensure that their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/protecting-the-product-design-with-ryan-shaffett-of-xq-manufacturing/">Protecting The Product Design with Ryan Shaffett of XQ Manufacturing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/protecting-the-product-design-with-ryan-shaffett-of-xq-manufacturing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/media.blubrry.com/10k_collective/content.blubrry.com/10k_collective/10k_006-ryan-pt2.mp3" length="25100120" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Protecting The Product Design The role of Patents in protecting your product design Protecting your Product Design doesn&#039;t necessarily start with  patent protections. One key is to minimise the chance of your supplier selling your product to other r...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Protecting The Product Design<br />
The role of Patents in protecting your product design<br />
Protecting your <a href="https://mammothpackaging.com/5-product-label-design-trends-to-watch-in-2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Product Design</a> doesn't necessarily start with  patent protections.<br />
One key is to minimise the chance of your supplier selling your product to other retailers. <br />
Ryan's team works hard on the selection of and relationship with suppliers to ensure that their factories don't do that.<br />
If you have your own Mold,  nobody else will use that, so that creates a lot of protection against getting copycat versions of your product out there.<br />
How to Protect your Product Design by Keeping a very close relationship  with your main suppliers<br />
The key is a  a very, very close relationship with middle supplier is that we consider Ryan considers them part  of his company and his mother calls the boss her Chinese son.<br />
Keeping the molds locked away is also part of protection against being copied. <br />
They have for example a very specific set of patterns for a client, which are in locked tubes for when they are needed.<br />
How about the “no” vs. Honesty thing?<br />
Mostly suppliers will tell you they can do something when in reality they can do ⅔ of what you want.<br />
Pin down the suppliers - make them repeat things in contracts and in writing.<br />
To be  sure they can hit your specifications - put in testing!<br />
Solution:1<br />
Sample sample sample!<br />
Core QC point - make sure the supplier don't mass produce a product until you’ve approved the sample!<br />
Chinese mentality of “cha abs dour”-'close enough' - is the biggest enemy.<br />
Quality control and protecting your product's quality<br />
Traditionally been so cheap to make stuff that the mentality is that it's cheaper and faster to make an approximate version initially. Then they will try to get the samples approved by the buyer. And if they have to, just redo it.<br />
QC - not just Pre-Shipment Inspection<br />
Process - Say do a tent, custom plastic:<br />
<br />
 	* Send client fabric strips<br />
 	* Make prototype with factory<br />
 	* Then if think understand what client was after and custom weave hundreds of rolls<br />
<br />
Be part of the process - sometimes prototype throws up new issues, eg,<br />
Didn’t think about how thick the fabric would need to be.<br />
Where are you at in the process? <br />
Prototype<br />
Sample<br />
Order process<br />
Production sample<br />
There is always a tension there<br />
Eg need tent in very specific colour etc.<br />
minimum to weave or dye a fabric - $1000s<br />
How approx do you need your prototype to be?<br />
Ryan has even been developing a product with his daughter!<br />
What sort of Custom Manufacturing service do you offer at XQ?<br />
Our service advantages help navigate some of the challenges associated with <a href="https://10kcollective.com/custom-manufacturing-for-amazon-with-ryan-shaffett-of-xq-manufacturing-part-1/">custom manufacturing</a>:<br />
Protecting your Product Design<br />
1- We do not sell privately developed products to other parties like many China based factories.<br />
Do you deal with freight?<br />
Usually to ship the smallest thing ocean you will pay over $700 due to the 1 time costs of import export, but we take on all these fees as part of the total container cost.<br />
2 - we have monthly consolidated ocean containers that allow give our clients low shipping cost options to our US warehouse.<br />
3 - We have a US company that acts as the importer so thus our US clients can pay our US company and not have to deal with international transfers, customs importing, shipping logistics, etc.  We can ship all the way to FBA for our clients.<br />
4- We are familiar with duty rates and import restrictions and can advise on all this or for our clients who wish ...]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>34:52</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9671</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Custom manufacturing for Amazon with Ryan Shaffett of XQ manufacturing – part 1</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/custom-manufacturing-for-amazon-with-ryan-shaffett-of-xq-manufacturing-part-1/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/custom-manufacturing-for-amazon-with-ryan-shaffett-of-xq-manufacturing-part-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 05:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Custom Product Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?post_type=10k&#038;p=6565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Custom manufacturing for Amazon Ryan Shaffett&#8217;s Custom manufacturing Background Ryan been living in China for 18 years &#8211; running biz there for 12 years. Started as a traditional manufacturer. XQ has a handful of clients &#8211; medium sized US companies, sporting goods industries. They’ve seen the trend towards FBA. Is Custom Manufacturing something that FBA [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/custom-manufacturing-for-amazon-with-ryan-shaffett-of-xq-manufacturing-part-1/">Custom manufacturing for Amazon with Ryan Shaffett of XQ manufacturing – part 1</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/custom-manufacturing-for-amazon-with-ryan-shaffett-of-xq-manufacturing-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/media.blubrry.com/10k_collective/content.blubrry.com/10k_collective/10k_005-ryan-pt1.mp3" length="24779441" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Custom manufacturing for Amazon - Ryan Shaffett&#039;s Custom manufacturing Background  Ryan been living in China for 18 years - running biz there for 12 years. Started as a traditional manufacturer. XQ has a handful of clients - medium sized US compani...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Custom manufacturing for Amazon<br />
<br />
Ryan Shaffett's Custom manufacturing Background <br />
Ryan been living in China for 18 years - running biz there for 12 years.<br />
Started as a traditional manufacturer.<br />
XQ has a handful of clients - medium sized US companies, sporting goods industries.<br />
They’ve seen the trend towards FBA.<br />
Is Custom Manufacturing something that FBA Businesses are doing more of?<br />
XQ have one key client fully FBA based business.<br />
But they are increasingly tweak services to meet FBA clients<br />
Most clients go from Private Label to custom manufacturing.<br />
What brings clients to you?<br />
The best clients have good people who communicate well.<br />
It can be very complicated to work with a Chinese factory to develop own products.<br />
Ryan tries to save a lot of hassle.<br />
They can reduce own staff in own country.<br />
What are the key distinctions between Custom Manufacturing for Amazon and Private Label? <br />
Advantages of Custom Manufacturing for Amazon<br />
<br />
 	* Truly unique<br />
 	* As opposed to Private Label -which can be an exercise in  “who can push the most product?”<br />
 	* Higher profit<br />
 	* Know niche read clients feedback<br />
 	* How it needs tweaking<br />
 	* Dealing with PL manufacturers<br />
 	* You are the mould owner -<br />
 	* If you develop a product - I’m going to charge the client for development costs.<br />
 	* Different price structure<br />
<br />
Summaries of Pros and cons of Custom Manufacturing<br />
The advantages to a privately developed product are:<br />
1 - It is very hard to hijack/copycat<br />
2- Often margins are much higher with privately developed products.<br />
3 - You can tweak it with all the features you know the market wants.<br />
What are the main downsides?<br />
Disadvantages:<br />
1- Minimums tend to be higher, like investing at least $2,000 or more on an order.  Large plastic molds can cost up to $10,000 and more.<br />
2 - You have to wait between 1-4 months to get your product in hand.<br />
Downsides of custom manufacturing for Amazon<br />
Time<br />
<br />
 	* Prototyping<br />
 	* Mold development is time consuming (could take a month)<br />
 	* Typical turnaround 1-2 weeks china<br />
 	* Every project different<br />
 	* 1-4 months or longer if multiple prototypes<br />
<br />
Money <br />
Plast ic inc molding costs $1K-10K<br />
No top end<br />
It's a Barrier for small FBA sellers<br />
How many units<br />
Small key shared objects can be tricky.<br />
You Can’t try out the market<br />
<br />
 	* It’s an upfront commitment<br />
 	* You might try a single cavity mould<br />
 	* Then develop a twenty piece mould<br />
 	* If product bigger than a breadbox everything is a one cavity mould<br />
 	* Manufacture costs<br />
<br />
Different manufacturing techniques<br />
Some clients are already very expert - detailed CAD drawings etc.<br />
Also work with clients who have hand sketched drawings and a concept<br />
XQ manufacturing will have a conversation<br />
Multi material products <br />
These are great but A bit more complex<br />
Basic types of multi material products include some basic electronics sometimes<br />
That's where the initial investment goes into developing the printed circuit board design. <br />
Wood<br />
Wood based products - fairly easy<br />
A lot of plastic and rubber products are also quite straight forward.<br />
Extrusion - tube, board etc. - is often used.<br />
They have lower costs than plastic injection moulding.<br />
Metal<br />
Machining  is used for metalwork (but also for plastic). Machined metal is often huge - for large components, Casting is also common.  Forging and bending are other common techniques.<br />
Textiles<br />
Textiles - have own in house general assembly and own textile factory usually.<br />
This would apply to,  for example, Bags and tents.]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>34:25</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">9672</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
