<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0"

	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Amazon FBA Private Label - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
	<atom:link href="https://amazingfba.com/category/amazon-fba/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/amazon-fba/</link>
	<description>Amazon Coach &#38; Mastermind Convenor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 14:50:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Amazing-FBA-new-logo-no-white-background-1-e1656858629506.png?fit=150%2C150&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Amazon FBA Private Label - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
	<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/amazon-fba/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<atom:link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
	<itunes:summary>Do you sell private label or custom products on Amazon UK, USA or Europe? Or are you gearing up to do it? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you are struggling to grow sales, seeing profits erode and feel a long way from a sellable valuable business, we can help. If you&#039;re already killing it, why not grow faster and make even more cash? &lt;br /&gt;
Either way, you&#039;re in the right place. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our experts answer these questions and more - experts like Greg Mercer of Jungle Scout, Will Tjernlund, Manuel Becvar, Chris Green, Kevin King, and many many more. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whether you are trying to get Amazon product research right; help sourcing from China; optimizing Amazon listings; dealing with  Amazon PPC (aka Amazon ads) - we&#039;ve got you covered!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you&#039;re UK based and you want to sell in UK or USA; and if you&#039;re US based and you&#039;re curious about - or selling in - UK or Europe, you can&#039;t afford to miss the detailed insights you&#039;ll get.</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
	<itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>Michael Veazey</itunes:name>
	</itunes:owner>
	<copyright>&#xA9;Michael Veazey 2015-2022</copyright>
	<podcast:license>&#xA9;Michael Veazey 2015-2022</podcast:license>
	<podcast:medium>podcast</podcast:medium>
	<itunes:subtitle>Amazing FBA Amazon and ECommerce Podcast, for Amazon Private Label Sellers, Shopify, Magento or Woocommerce business owners, and other e-commerce sellers and digital entrepreneurs.</itunes:subtitle>
	<image>
		<title>Amazon FBA Private Label - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
		<url>https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg</url>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/amazon-fba/</link>
	</image>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Careers" />
	</itunes:category>
	<googleplay:category text="Business"/>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Marketing" />
	</itunes:category>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Entrepreneurship" />
	</itunes:category>
	<rawvoice:rating>TV-G</rawvoice:rating>
	<rawvoice:location>London, England</rawvoice:location>
	<podcast:location>London, England</podcast:location>
	<podcast:podping usesPodping="true" />
	<rawvoice:subscribe feed="https://amazingfba.com/category/amazon-fba/feed/" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/ug/podcast/amazing-fba/id1030237683" spotify="https://open.spotify.com/show/32Cryk51sxVlF03B38UeoJ" amazon_music="https://music.amazon.co.uk/podcasts/3237ef11-0180-45a2-adff-2b4ab89267b5/amazing-fba-amazon-and-ecommerce-podcast-for-amazon-private-label-sellers-shopify-magento-or-woocommerce-business-owners-and-other-e-commerce-sellers-and-digital-entrepreneurs"></rawvoice:subscribe>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">203239326</site>	<item>
		<title>Amazon Tiktok integration (Amazon Newsday 10 Sep 2024)</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-tiktok-integration-amazon-newsday-10-sep-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-tiktok-integration-amazon-newsday-10-sep-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 05:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Michael Veazey Welcome to Amazon Newsday. I&#8217;m your host, Michael Veazey. Today, a couple of stories that are not in the last couple of weeks, but they were so important, we didn&#8217;t want you to miss them. Amazon Tiktok Integration Announced Amazon TikTok integration. On the 9th of August, Amazon and TikTok officially announced their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/amazon-tiktok-integration-amazon-newsday-10-sep-2024/">Amazon Tiktok integration (Amazon Newsday 10 Sep 2024)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-tiktok-integration-amazon-newsday-10-sep-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Amazon_Tiktok_integration_Amazon_Newsday_10_Sep_2024_.mp3" length="3627141" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Michael Veazey Welcome to Amazon Newsday. I&#039;m your host, Michael Veazey. Today, a couple of stories that are not in the last couple of weeks, but they were so important, we didn&#039;t want you to miss them.    Amazon Tiktok Integration Announced    </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Michael Veazey Welcome to Amazon Newsday. I'm your host, Michael Veazey. Today, a couple of stories that are not in the last couple of weeks, but they were so important, we didn't want you to miss them.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon Tiktok Integration Announced<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon TikTok integration.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
On the 9th of August, Amazon and TikTok officially announced their partnership, enabling users to discover and purchase Amazon products directly within the TikTok app.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The integration allows TikTok users to see Amazon product recommendations on their For You feed. Users can link their TikTok and Amazon accounts through a secure one time setup process. Once accounts are linked, Amazon customers can then complete checkout within TikTok without leaving the app, providing a faster and more frictionless experience.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Users in the U S. who linked their accounts will see real time pricing, primary eligibility, delivery experts, and product details on select Amazon product ads in TikTok.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
"Project Handshake"<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This partnership is part of Amazon's Project Handshake, a broader Amazon strategy which aims to merge social media with e commerce.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Similar integrations have been made with platforms like Meta and Snapchat. For Amazon sellers, this integration could open up new opportunities to reach younger audiences through TikTok, potentially making sponsored display and DSP ads more effective.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This integration is initially launching only in the United States with no specific timeline provided for expansion to other regions. This partnership represents a significant step in integrating e commerce with social media, potentially reshaping online shopping behaviors and offering new avenues for brands to reach consumers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon required to recall unsafe products<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon has been required to recall unsafe products.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
In a landmark decision, the U. S. Consumer Product Safety Commission, the CSPC, has ruled that Amazon is legally responsible for hazardous products sold by third party sellers through its Fulfillment by Amazon program. This July 29th ruling classifies Amazon as a distributor under the Consumer Product Safety Act, making it liable for over 400, 000 potentially dangerous items sold on its platform.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The case focused on products like flammable children's sleepwear, faulty carbon monoxide detectors and unsafe hairdryers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
As a result, Amazon must now develop plans to notify purchasers and the public about these hazards and provide refunds or replacements.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Wider implications for e-commerce sellers<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This decision could have far reaching implications for other e commerce platforms, potentially subjecting them to similar notice reporting and recall obligations as traditional retailers. It underscores the CPSC's commitment to enforcing compliance across all<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
parties in the consumer product distribution chain.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon plans to appeal the ruling, arguing that it had already taken swift action to warn consumers and offer refunds when notified of safety issues. However, the CPSC found these measures inadequate, emphasizing the importance of public notice for all potentially affected customers.<br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>601</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>601</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>3:47</itunes:duration>
		<podcast:transcript url="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Amazon-Tiktok-integration-Amazon-Newsday-10-Sep-2024.txt" language="en-gb" type="text/plain" rel="captions" />
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">15026</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unfulfillable FBA inventory to be removed after 23 days</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/unfulfillable-fba-inventory-to-be-removed-after-23-days/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/unfulfillable-fba-inventory-to-be-removed-after-23-days/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 10:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Amazon Newsday 3 Sep 2024 Unfulfillable FBA inventory to be removed after 23 days Unfulfillable FBA inventory is to be removed after 23 days. Amazon is updating its FBA inventory-required removals policy. Amazon claims this is to create more room for seller products and to help sellers to save on storage fees. Starting on September [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/unfulfillable-fba-inventory-to-be-removed-after-23-days/">Unfulfillable FBA inventory to be removed after 23 days</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/unfulfillable-fba-inventory-to-be-removed-after-23-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Amazon_Newsday_3_Sep_2024.mp3" length="3920943" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Amazon Newsday 3 Sep 2024        Unfulfillable FBA inventory to be removed after 23 days    Unfulfillable FBA inventory is to be removed after 23 days.    Amazon is updating its FBA inventory-required removals policy.    </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Amazon Newsday 3 Sep 2024<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Unfulfillable FBA inventory to be removed after 23 days<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Unfulfillable FBA inventory is to be removed after 23 days.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon is updating its FBA inventory-required removals policy.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon claims this is to create more room for seller products and to help sellers to save on storage fees.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Starting on September the 16th 2024, if sellers have not enabled automated unfulfillable settings in the UK or the EU, Amazon will dispose of or donate unfulfillable inventory after 23 days' notice instead of the current 30 days.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
To avoid disposal, Amazon says sellers can create a manual removal order or configure automated settings to either liquidate the inventory to recover some value straight away or return inventory and have it sent to a seller return to address or a third-party freight forwarder.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Once they create a disposal order after 23 days' notice, Amazon warns it cannot be cancelled.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Change to the digital services tax charges from October.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
On October the 1st, 2024, Amazon will introduce a digital services fee for digital services taxes, DST that are implemented by the governments of Canada, the UK, France, Italy, and Spain. The typical DST Rate is 2 percent in the UK and 3 percent in Canada, France, Italy, and Spain.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Since 2021, Amazon has apparently accounted for DST by increasing selling on Amazon fees in the UK, France, Italy, and Spain, and by increasing fulfilment by Amazon fees in the UK and France, but starting from October 1st, Amazon will reduce those fees and account for this cost by introducing a standalone digital services fee.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
DST or digital services taxes charges are unpredictable as they vary based on the location of the seller's business, the location of the buyer and other factors. And so Amazon has decided rather than basing the digital services fee on those variables, which will create an unpredictable unpredictable business impact, um, Amazon will introduce a fixed digital services fee only based on the seller's location and the store in which the sellers sell.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Where to see the digital services fee applied to seller's orders<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
If sellers wish to see where their digital services fees are being applied to the orders from September the 1st, sellers can preview the fee in the revenue calculator and starting on October the 1st, sellers will be able to track digital services fees via the transaction view in the payments reports.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
In order to view the fees across different stores and different countries, the SKU economics report will provide historical proceeds from sales. Returns fees and ad spend and net proceeds by SKU for each store in which the sellers sell.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Change to coupon code stacking settings<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Changes to coupon code stacking settings.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon has added an extra setting to give sellers control over whether coupons can be stacked by consumers. Stacking coupons means that, for example, a 20 percent offer could be combined with a 5 off offer to give a consumer a larger discount on an item than a seller intended.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon have created a new tool called Stacked Promotions Enablement. This tool enables sellers to choose how they stack coupons, percentage off, or buy one get one promotions. It's thought this will be particularly useful for protecting sellers on high-volume days such as Prime Day. <br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>598</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>598</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>4:05</itunes:duration>
		<podcast:transcript url="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Amazon-Newsday-3-Sep-2024.txt" language="en-gb" type="text/plain" rel="captions" />
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">15023</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazing FBA Newsday &#8211; Amazon Drones Annoy Texas Residents</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/amazing-fba-newsday-amazon-drones-annoy-texas-residents/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/amazing-fba-newsday-amazon-drones-annoy-texas-residents/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Amazon Newsday 27 August 2024 Amazon Newsday 27 August 2024 If it&#8217;s Tuesday, it&#8217;s Amazing FBA Newsday, the show for Amazon seller news. Here&#8217;s your host, Michael Veazey! This is Michael Veazey and welcome to Amazon Newsday. Amazon Delivery Drone Noise Annoys Texas Residents Amazon delivery drone noise has been annoying some residents in Texas. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/amazing-fba-newsday-amazon-drones-annoy-texas-residents/">Amazing FBA Newsday &#8211; Amazon Drones Annoy Texas Residents</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/amazing-fba-newsday-amazon-drones-annoy-texas-residents/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Amazon_Newsday_27_August_2024.mp3" length="3466209" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Amazon Newsday 27 August 2024    Amazon Newsday 27 August 2024    If it&#039;s Tuesday, it&#039;s Amazing FBA Newsday, the show for Amazon seller news.    Here&#039;s your host, Michael Veazey!    This is Michael Veazey and welcome to Amazon Newsday.    </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Amazon Newsday 27 August 2024<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon Newsday 27 August 2024<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
If it's Tuesday, it's Amazing FBA Newsday, the show for Amazon seller news.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Here's your host, Michael Veazey!<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This is Michael Veazey and welcome to Amazon Newsday.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon Delivery Drone Noise Annoys Texas Residents<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon delivery drone noise has been annoying some residents in Texas.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Residents of College Station, Texas are troubled by noise pollution from Amazon's delivery zones, a concern as Amazon seeks to expand its Prime Air program. Amazon has asked the Federal Aviation Administration, the FAA, to increase drone flights from 200 a day to 469 per day, which has raised concerns amongst residents living near the drone facility.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The buzzing noise from drones is a significant issue, potentially leading to stricter regulations or bans that could hinder Amazon's expansion plans. Amazon began drone deliveries in 2022 in College Station and in Lockford, California, and it aims to improve community relations by possibly relocating drones and their ports away from residential areas.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The City of College Station is collaborating with Amazon to find industrial zone locations for drone operations and Amazon is developing a quieter drone model, the MK30, to reduce the noise. Despite the noise concerns, the drone delivery program has been successful with no reported crashes or injuries and is seen as innovative and efficient by local officials.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Drone delivery is still in its early stages and is facing regulatory, technical and public acceptance challenges, but it holds potential for future growth as a supplement to traditional methods.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon to bring back Prime Big Deal Days this October<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon announced it's bringing back its Prime Big Deal Days sales event this October. Prime Big Deal Days return this October to kick off the holiday season for Amazon this autumn and fall. Only Prime members will have access to early holiday deals across popular categories, including deep discounts on products from top brands.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The celebration will take place in 19 countries, including Australia, most European countries, including France, Germany, and the United Kingdom, and in North America, Canada, Canada and the United States.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon Launches “FBA Grade and Resell” programmer<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon launches FBA grade and resell program. Amazon is launching a program to enable, uh, sellers on its platform to regrade and resell rejected and secondhand inventory. The way it will work is that after ingraining in grade and resell eligible FBA returns will be inspected to see if they can be relisted with one of the four conditions, like new, very good, good, or acceptable.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Amazon will inspect packaging, confirm the item matches the description, test the items condition, check for any signs of use and assess any damage. When the item is relisted through grade and resell, Amazon will provide customers with a detailed description of its condition. This includes information about minor imperfections, packaging details, and functional functionality.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
With grade and resell, Amazon says the three. Selling points are that you can recover value, that is turn customer returns into sales, set it and forget it with a streamlined customer returns management and supporting, of course, sustainability and enhancing reputation with customers by offering pre owned products.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Thanks so much for listening to today's show, stay tuned next week for our ongoing Newsday updates. This has been Michael Veazey for AmazingFBA.<br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>594</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>594</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>3:37</itunes:duration>
		<podcast:transcript url="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Amazon-Newsday-27-August-2024.txt" language="en" type="text/plain" rel="captions" />
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">15008</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stop Wasting Ad Spend! Improve Your Ecommerce ROI</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/improve-ecommerce-roi/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/improve-ecommerce-roi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon Wholesale FBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ecommerce brands face a constant challenge: maximizing return on investment (ROI) for their advertising spend. In 2023-2024, while social, search, and display advertising witnessed impressive returns, the current trend reveals a worrying decline. The knee-jerk reaction might be to throw more money at the problem, but that&#8217;s a recipe for wasted resources. The key lies [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/improve-ecommerce-roi/">Stop Wasting Ad Spend! Improve Your Ecommerce ROI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/improve-ecommerce-roi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Jennifer_Stuton-Episode_02-auphonic.mp3" length="28056763" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Ecommerce brands face a constant challenge: maximizing return on investment (ROI) for their advertising spend. In 2023-2024, while social, search, and display advertising witnessed impressive returns, the current trend reveals a worrying decline.</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Ecommerce brands face a constant challenge: maximizing return on investment (ROI) for their advertising spend. In 2023-2024, while social, search, and display advertising witnessed impressive returns, the current trend reveals a worrying decline. The knee-jerk reaction might be to throw more money at the problem, but that's a recipe for wasted resources.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The key lies in optimizing your approach. This guide dives deep into common mistakes e-commerce brands make and equips you with actionable strategies to improve your ad ROI, even with limited capital.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00] - The Importance of Nurturing Existing Customers[01:02] - Introduction to E-Commerce Marketing Issues[01:44] - Overuse of AI and Need for Re-evaluation[03:10] - Lack of Customer Retention Strategies[03:54] - Bad Habits Growing in Good Times[05:11] - Relying on Amazon Data vs. Other Sources[06:08] - Oversaturation on Meta/Facebook Advertising[07:20] - Lack of Holistic Media Mix Approach[07:58] - The Concept of a 'Richer Message'[09:31] - Explaining the Marketing Funnel[11:09] - Simplifying Messaging for Customers[12:55] - Understanding Media Efficiency Metrics[14:11] - Importance of Frequency in Advertising[15:00] - Consistency in Branding and Messaging[17:04] - Bright Marketing's Services Explained<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Rethink the AI Hype: Leverage Data for Smarter Decisions<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
AI has become a major trend in marketing, but relying solely on it can be a costly mistake. Here's why:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Data Blindness: AI tools are powerful, but they can't replace human analysis of campaign data. Understanding what's performing well and what's not allows for targeted adjustments.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Customer Disconnect: AI-driven targeting might miss the mark. Analyze past purchases to identify upsell, resell, and cross-sell opportunities. Don't forget – customer churn is a hidden cost. Analyze your data to identify and nurture your audience effectively.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Many brands rely on data from different platforms without a central source of truth. Consider implementing robust tagging and tracking systems in Google Analytics and Google Search Console to gain a holistic view.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Beyond Facebook Ads: Exploring the Evolving Media Landscape<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Meta (Facebook) and Instagram, while popular, are becoming saturated, leading to diminishing returns. Here's what you need to consider:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Audience Targeting: Success hinges on reaching the right audience on the right platform. Don't blindly buy placements based on cost alone. Understand where your target audience spends their time online.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Holistic Approach: Many agencies solely focus on SEO and PPC, neglecting Amazon platforms. A complete media mix considers the entire customer journey, including top-of-funnel strategies like TV, billboards, sponsorships, and influencer marketing.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Media Buying 101: Understanding Efficiency and Effectiveness<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Media buying involves acquiring ad space across various platforms. Here are key concepts to grasp:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Cost per Mille (CPM): This metric indicates the efficiency of your buy. It represents the cost per thousand impressions.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The Power of the Marketing Funnel: Tailoring Your Message for Impact<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The customer journey can be visualized as a marketing funnel with distinct stages:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Awareness: Introduce your brand and product to potential customers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Consideration: Nurture interest and highlight the value proposition.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Preference: Differentiate yourself from competitors and establish brand preference.<br />
<br />
<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>566</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>566</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Stop Wasting Ad Spend! Improve Your Ecommerce ROI</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>29:14</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14787</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unlock Success: Your Ultimate Amazon Affiliate Program Guide to Recruit Affiliates</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-affiliate-program-recruit-affiliates/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-affiliate-program-recruit-affiliates/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 07:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scaling An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;ve set up your Amazon affiliate program, products are ready, commissions are tempting, but your inbox is eerily quiet. Where are the eager affiliates, the brand advocates, the traffic champions you envisioned? Fear not, e-commerce warriors, for this guide unlocks the secrets to recruiting the perfect allies for your Amazon success story. [00:00:00] Introduction to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/amazon-affiliate-program-recruit-affiliates/">Unlock Success: Your Ultimate Amazon Affiliate Program Guide to Recruit Affiliates</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/amazon-affiliate-program-recruit-affiliates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/01_External_traffic_via_affiliate_marketing_for_Amazon_Sellers_updated-auphonic.mp3" length="34404727" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>You&#039;ve set up your Amazon affiliate program, products are ready, commissions are tempting, but your inbox is eerily quiet. Where are the eager affiliates, the brand advocates, the traffic champions you envisioned? Fear not, e-commerce warriors,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[You've set up your Amazon affiliate program, products are ready, commissions are tempting, but your inbox is eerily quiet. Where are the eager affiliates, the brand advocates, the traffic champions you envisioned? Fear not, e-commerce warriors, for this guide unlocks the secrets to recruiting the perfect allies for your Amazon success story.<br />
[00:00:00] Introduction to the Importance of Flexibility in Commission Rates and Sending Products to Influencers for Effective Promotion<br />
[00:02:26] Discussion on Recruiting Affiliates and the Three-Pronged Approach for Scaling the Program<br />
[00:03:40] Emphasizing the Use of a Network or Marketplace (Like Levanta) to Access a Large Pool of Affiliates<br />
[00:04:16] Insights into the Outbound Recruitment Strategy, Including Using a Tool to Filter and Send Personalized Invitations to Potential Affiliates<br />
[00:05:07] Importance of Being Flexible with Commission Rates and Sending Products, Especially for Influencers and Content Creators<br />
[00:06:06] Discussion on Creating Compelling Offers for Affiliates, Including the Concept of Offering a Lifetime Supply of Products<br />
[00:08:42] The Significance of Building Relationships with Affiliates and How Goodwill Plays a Crucial Role in Affiliate Partnerships<br />
[00:12:12] Explanation of External Recruitment Strategy, Involving Discovery, Outreach, and Activation to Bring in New Affiliates<br />
[00:18:24] The Third Prong, a Passive Strategy for Brands With an Omni-Channel Presence, Involving Promoting the Amazon Affiliate Program on Their Websites<br />
[00:23:21] Summary of Levanta's Role in Automating Affiliate Program Management and Information<br />
The 3-Pronged Approach to Affiliate Recruitment:<br />
<br />
<br />
 	<br />
Network Advantage: Leverage established platforms like Levanta to access a pre-vetted pool of affiliates. Filter by audience size, niche, and engagement to find your perfect match. Remember, personalization trumps mass blasts! Be flexible with commission rates and consider product gifts for influencers.<br />
<br />
 	<br />
Beyond the Network: Don't limit yourself! Actively seek out affiliates through external marketing. Use discovery tools, personalize your outreach (DMs, LinkedIn, emails), and track your efforts. Levanta offers a branded signup link, streamlining the onboarding process for your recruits.<br />
<br />
 	<br />
Make it Visible: Place your affiliate signup link prominently across your online presence. Include it on your DTC website, social media profiles, and even Amazon listing descriptions. Accessibility is key to attracting potential partners.<br />
<br />
<br />
Building Relationships, Not Just Commissions:<br />
While financial incentives are important, remember, genuine connections create long-term success. Offer exclusive deals, early access to new products, and even lifetime supply options for top performers. Go beyond CPA – consider flat fees for valuable affiliates.<br />
Navigating the Amazon Affiliate Landscape:<br />
Unlike the Wild West of early internet advertising, the Amazon ecosystem offers built-in fraud protection. Focus on finding quality affiliates who align with your brand and target audience, rather than worrying about scams. Don't be afraid to work with smaller influencers – their dedicated communities can offer surprising results.<br />
Levanta: Your Affiliate Management Ally:<br />
Levanta streamlines affiliate onboarding, tracking, communication, and management. Imagine automated workflows, detailed reports, and a dedicated support team, all under one roof.<br />
Empower Your Brand with the Power of Affiliates:<br />
Download Levanta's free ebooks:<br />
<br />
<br />
 	"<a href="https://d2hc-h04.na1.hs-sales-engage.com/Ctc/W4+23284/d2HC-h04/Jll2-6qcW7Y8-PT6lZ3mqW8hl62Z2BTYd9W1qC1sr53Q4pSW8s4wnf3Jvc-kW3hHy9V4RJWhsW5SqRhX5kmzNqW8jT-wb6Ndm9PW8T9vFM2fG-NSW8CWmY73T9lW1W4Y2WyW78hbzlW8MKhjW5sYl2VW2QwymY4HNdfNW7JLgxs56...]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>524</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>524</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Unlock Success: Your Ultimate Amazon Affiliate Program Guide to Recruit Affiliates</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>35:50</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14564</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Charity for Business – Adding Charitable Giving to Your E-commerce Work Part I of II</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/charity-for-business-adding-charitable-giving-to-your-e-commerce-work-part-i-of-ii/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/charity-for-business-adding-charitable-giving-to-your-e-commerce-work-part-i-of-ii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 07:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=13962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In this 2-part episode we discuss adding charitable giving to  your e-commerce work and how it can help change the world, strengthen your brand, and build a better business. We also discuss challenges and cautionary tales too. You’ll learn Common legal structures for charitable work Create ideas for giving (beyond cash) to charities Michael &#38; [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/charity-for-business-adding-charitable-giving-to-your-e-commerce-work-part-i-of-ii/">Charity for Business – Adding Charitable Giving to Your E-commerce Work Part I of II</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/charity-for-business-adding-charitable-giving-to-your-e-commerce-work-part-i-of-ii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">13962</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brand Identity Definition - eCommerce Brand Strategy</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/brand-identity-definition/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/brand-identity-definition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 07:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Custom Product Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=13782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brand Identity Definition If you&#8217;re selling your products on a website, it&#8217;s important to give your brand an identity. The best way to do this is with a brand strategy. A brand strategy can help you understand what makes your product different and how to communicate that to customers. It also helps you decide when [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/brand-identity-definition/">Brand Identity Definition &#8211; eCommerce Brand Strategy</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/brand-identity-definition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/394_Brand_Identity_Definition-eCommerce_Brand_Strategy_JB-auphonic.mp3" length="32215457" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Brand Identity Definition If you&#039;re selling your products on a website, it&#039;s important to give your brand an identity. The best way to do this is with a brand strategy. A brand strategy can help you understand what makes your product different and how...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Brand Identity Definition<br />
If you're selling your products on a website, it's important to give your brand an identity. The best way to do this is with a brand strategy. A brand strategy can help you understand what makes your product different and how to communicate that to customers. It also helps you decide when it's time for a rebranding project! What is a brand identity definition? A brand identity is everything your customers associate with your products and company. A brand strategy is a plan that helps you decide how to communicate your brand. This includes things like what your logo will look like, what colors you'll use and how you're going to talk about yourself. It's all about understanding who your customers are, what they need from your product, and how you can meet those needs better than anyone else!<br />
<br />
Timestamps for Podcast<br />
[00:35:02] Intro: Curated Marketplace For Custom Design<br />
[01:41:77] What is Brand Identity?<br />
[03:37:07] <a href="http://www.Amazingfba.com/crowdspring">Crowdspring</a> Offers A Wide Variety of Designer Types<br />
[06:49:41] Brand Perception is Guided By The Companies<br />
[09:37:82] The Product Has To Be Good But So Does The Whole Experience<br />
[12:07:36] What Are The Steps In Creating A Brand Identity From The Beginning?<br />
[12:38:30] The Core Brand : Visual Identity<br />
[14:03:35] Transferring Your Design Into Packaging<br />
[16:37:32] Brand Consistency<br />
[18:13:38] How Do We Get Consistency?<br />
[20:53:53] How Do We Create Brand Guidelines? Is it Necessary to Hire Someone?<br />
[23:03:76] Branding and Packaging<br />
[27:22:64] <a href="http://www.Amazingfba.com/crowdspring">Crowdspring</a> and their Services<br />
<a href="http://www.Amazingfba.com/crowdspring">About our Guests- Jason Byer and Crowd Spring</a><br />
Are the  99 Designs of e-commerce with two tweaks. Firstly, they have a very highly selected set of designers.  Secondly, their designers  include  industrial designers (aka product designers).<br />
<br />
 	* Get Your <a href="http://www.amazingfba.com/BrandGrade">Free Custom Brand Report Here</a> !<br />
 	* Get a $35 Off Your First Product Here : <a href="http://www.Amazingfba.com/crowdspring">Get It Here</a> ! <br />
<br />
What Does a Successful Brand Identity Look Like?<br />
If you want to build a successful brand identity, you need to start with the basics. Brand identity is the sum of all the elements that make up your brand. This includes not only what you say about your business and how it’s doing, but also how others perceive these things by looking at your logo and website, reading some of your content on social media, or watching videos on YouTube.<br />
<br />
A successful brand identity is one where all these components work together as part of an overall strategy that helps customers understand what makes this company different from others in its market niche. It does this through:<br />
<br />
 	A well-defined promise or value proposition;<br />
 	Clear messaging (whether verbal or visual);<br />
 	Consistent branding across platforms; and<br />
 	Appropriate use of colours, fonts and imagery<br />
<br />
How to Create a Great Brand Identity for Your eCommerce Business<br />
A great brand identity is one that is recognizable and distinct. This means that it should be consistent across all channels, including your website, social media platforms, packaging and marketing campaigns.<br />
<br />
Being consistent with your brand identity will allow you to establish trust among consumers. That helps them feel comfortable making purchases from you. Your logo is the key component of this. Make sure it stands out from other logos. That way, customers can easily identify it as belonging to your company. Your logo should also be memorable so that customers don't forget about you after they've made their purchase.<br />
<br />
By using the same colors,]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>389</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>389</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title> Brand Identity Definition - eCommerce Brand Strategy</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>33:33</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">13782</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DTC Platform Choice and Blogging for Traffic</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/dtc-platform-choice-and-blogging-for-traffic/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/dtc-platform-choice-and-blogging-for-traffic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 12:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=12787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Adam Wright, is a long-time sufferer from Chronic Fatigue Syndrome and wanted to ensure he received all the essential nutrients to help him combat daily fatigue and brain fog. The search for the ultimate greens blend ended up with him creating his own formula alongside one of the top USA Nutritional manufacturers. A competitive Triathlete [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/dtc-platform-choice-and-blogging-for-traffic/">DTC Platform Choice and Blogging for Traffic</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/dtc-platform-choice-and-blogging-for-traffic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Ep_1_DTC_ecommerce_entrepreneurial_journey-auphonic.mp3" length="26126627" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Adam Wright, is a long-time sufferer from Chronic Fatigue Syndrome and wanted to ensure he received all the essential nutrients to help him combat daily fatigue and brain fog. - The search for the ultimate greens blend ended up with him creating his o...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[Adam Wright, is a long-time sufferer from Chronic Fatigue Syndrome and wanted to ensure he received all the essential nutrients to help him combat daily fatigue and brain fog.<br />
<br />
The search for the ultimate greens blend ended up with him creating his own formula alongside one of the top USA Nutritional manufacturers.<br />
<br />
A competitive Triathlete when he was younger, Adam became ill with Chronic Fatigue Syndrome and still suffers the symptoms today.<br />
<br />
Although not able to compete in long-distance running and triathlons anymore, Adam spent years studying sport physiology and nutrition at Brighton University under prominent physiologists and coaches of the day.<br />
<br />
Disillusioned with many supplement brands available today, he decided to create his own brand that he takes every day to support his health and well-being.<br />
<br />
&nbsp;<br />
What you’ll learn<br />
<br />
 	* Why start DTC not Amazon?<br />
 	* What platform and why?<br />
<br />
 	* Woocommerce<br />
 	* Shopify<br />
<br />
<br />
 	* How easy would it be to set up?<br />
 	* Traffic - Part 1<br />
 	* How did you get traffic?<br />
 	* How to reverse engineer your journey<br />
<br />
Resources<br />
<br />
 	* For the super greens for US customers<br />
<a href="http://www.supergreentonik.com">Super Green Tonik</a><br />
Code : AmazingFBA - 15%<br />
 	* Consultancy for those considering selling supplements find out more <a href="http://amazingfba.com/adamwright">here</a>! <br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>316</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>316</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>DTC Platform Choice and Blogging for Traffic</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>27:13</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">12787</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Improve Returning Customer Rate Part 2</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-improve-returning-customer-rate-part-2/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-improve-returning-customer-rate-part-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 07:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scaling An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=12767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>New e-commerce sellers always tell me they want more traffic to their website, and when I ask why – they say “I need more sales”. In this episode we’ll talk about how your returning customer rate directly impacts your conversion rate – 8 ways to improve your returning customer rate. What you’ll learn 9 Tips [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/how-to-improve-returning-customer-rate-part-2/">How to Improve Returning Customer Rate Part 2</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-improve-returning-customer-rate-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Part_2-How_to_Improve_Returning_Cusomter_Rate_TBC-auphonic.mp3" length="19119123" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>New e-commerce sellers always tell me they want more traffic to their website, and when I ask why – they say “I need more sales”. In this episode we’ll talk about how your returning customer rate directly impacts your conversion rate – 8 ways to improv...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[New e-commerce sellers always tell me they want more traffic to their website, and when I ask why – they say “I need more sales”. In this episode we’ll talk about how your returning customer rate directly impacts your conversion rate – 8 ways to improve your returning customer rate.<br />
What you’ll learn<br />
<br />
 	* 9 Tips For Increasing Your Returning Customer Rate<br />
 	* Why returning customer rate and e-commerce conversion rate are tightly correlated.<br />
 	* A recap of the conversion rate possibilities Frontier framework.<br />
 	* Why just 2 of our ways are advertising based strategies – and the others are free and/or more organic.<br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>312</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>312</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>How to Improve Returning Customer Rate Part 2</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>19:55</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">12767</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Business-to-Business Model in E-commerce with Daniel Shnaider of Anybiz and Talor Ofer</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/the-business-to-business-model-in-e-commerce-with-daniel-shnaider-of-anybiz-and-talor-ofer/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/the-business-to-business-model-in-e-commerce-with-daniel-shnaider-of-anybiz-and-talor-ofer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Von Leong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 07:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Amazon FBA Private Label]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scaling An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Selling An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=12757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>AnyBiz is a super smart marketing tool that brings the right people, information, and tools together to grow. AnyBiz connects businesses, and drive collaboration forward. Reaching potential customer is fast and super easy. Everything in one place. Database + Cold email campaign. A one-stop-shop to reach potential customers. Everything is in one place. Simple dashboard. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/the-business-to-business-model-in-e-commerce-with-daniel-shnaider-of-anybiz-and-talor-ofer/">The Business-to-Business Model in E-commerce with Daniel Shnaider of Anybiz and Talor Ofer</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/the-business-to-business-model-in-e-commerce-with-daniel-shnaider-of-anybiz-and-talor-ofer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/The_Business-to-Business_Model_in_E-commerce_with_Daniel_Shnaider_of_Anybiz_and_Talor_Ofer-auphonic.mp3" length="30554069" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>AnyBiz is a super smart marketing tool that brings the right people, information, and tools together to grow. AnyBiz connects businesses, and drive collaboration forward. - Reaching potential customer is fast and super easy. Everything in one place.</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
AnyBiz is a super smart marketing tool that brings the right people, information, and tools together to grow. AnyBiz connects businesses, and drive collaboration forward.<br />
<br />
Reaching potential customer is fast and super easy. Everything in one place. Database + Cold email campaign.<br />
<br />
A one-stop-shop to reach potential customers. Everything is in one place. Simple dashboard. Great results.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Daniel is the co founder of Anybiz , Talor is a collaborator and expert in getting into B2B sales<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
In this episode you'll learn:<br />
<br />
 	* Juicy outcomes of B2B<br />
 	* Problems with B2C<br />
 	* Valuing the Economic Benefits<br />
 	* Understanding your Brand Recognition<br />
 	* Find prospect companies<br />
 	* How to choose businesses<br />
 	* What do we say in the email?<br />
<br />
 	* The key is sending to the right person<br />
 	* Show that you understand their language and expectation<br />
 	* Clean and clear and short<br />
 	* No attachments<br />
<br />
<br />
 	* How do fine tune the targeting of the person?<br />
 	* Finding the right buyer in a big chain<br />
 	* Should you target big or smaller companies?<br />
<br />
Resources<br />
<br />
 	* <a href="http://www.amazingfba.com/anybiz">Contact Retail Empire and tell them we sent you and get a 20% off!</a><br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>310</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>310</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>The Business-to-Business Model in E-commerce with Daniel Shnaider of Anybiz and Talor Ofer</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>31:50</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">12757</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
