<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0"
xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/"
xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0"

	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Running An Ecommerce Business - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
	<atom:link href="https://amazingfba.com/category/running-an-ecommerce-business/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/running-an-ecommerce-business/</link>
	<description>Amazon Coach &#38; Mastermind Convenor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 23:10:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Amazing-FBA-new-logo-no-white-background-1-e1656858629506.png?fit=150%2C150&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Running An Ecommerce Business - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
	<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/running-an-ecommerce-business/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<atom:link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
	<itunes:summary>Do you sell private label or custom products on Amazon UK, USA or Europe? Or are you gearing up to do it? &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you are struggling to grow sales, seeing profits erode and feel a long way from a sellable valuable business, we can help. If you&#039;re already killing it, why not grow faster and make even more cash? &lt;br /&gt;
Either way, you&#039;re in the right place. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Our experts answer these questions and more - experts like Greg Mercer of Jungle Scout, Will Tjernlund, Manuel Becvar, Chris Green, Kevin King, and many many more. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Whether you are trying to get Amazon product research right; help sourcing from China; optimizing Amazon listings; dealing with  Amazon PPC (aka Amazon ads) - we&#039;ve got you covered!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you&#039;re UK based and you want to sell in UK or USA; and if you&#039;re US based and you&#039;re curious about - or selling in - UK or Europe, you can&#039;t afford to miss the detailed insights you&#039;ll get.</itunes:summary>
	<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
	<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
	<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
	<itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
	<itunes:owner>
		<itunes:name>Michael Veazey</itunes:name>
	</itunes:owner>
	<copyright>&#xA9;Michael Veazey 2015-2022</copyright>
	<podcast:license>&#xA9;Michael Veazey 2015-2022</podcast:license>
	<podcast:medium>podcast</podcast:medium>
	<itunes:subtitle>Amazing FBA Amazon and ECommerce Podcast, for Amazon Private Label Sellers, Shopify, Magento or Woocommerce business owners, and other e-commerce sellers and digital entrepreneurs.</itunes:subtitle>
	<image>
		<title>Running An Ecommerce Business - Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</title>
		<url>https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg</url>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/category/running-an-ecommerce-business/</link>
	</image>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Careers" />
	</itunes:category>
	<googleplay:category text="Business"/>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Marketing" />
	</itunes:category>
	<itunes:category text="Business">
		<itunes:category text="Entrepreneurship" />
	</itunes:category>
	<rawvoice:rating>TV-G</rawvoice:rating>
	<rawvoice:location>London, England</rawvoice:location>
	<podcast:location>London, England</podcast:location>
	<podcast:podping usesPodping="true" />
	<rawvoice:subscribe feed="https://amazingfba.com/category/running-an-ecommerce-business/feed/" itunes="http://itunes.apple.com/ug/podcast/amazing-fba/id1030237683" spotify="https://open.spotify.com/show/32Cryk51sxVlF03B38UeoJ" amazon_music="https://music.amazon.co.uk/podcasts/3237ef11-0180-45a2-adff-2b4ab89267b5/amazing-fba-amazon-and-ecommerce-podcast-for-amazon-private-label-sellers-shopify-magento-or-woocommerce-business-owners-and-other-e-commerce-sellers-and-digital-entrepreneurs"></rawvoice:subscribe>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">203239326</site>	<item>
		<title>Make Confident business decisions: should you &#8220;Follow the numbers&#8221;?</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/make-confident-business-decisions-should-you-follow-the-numbers/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/make-confident-business-decisions-should-you-follow-the-numbers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 05:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Should entrepreneurs always &#8220;Follow the numbers&#8221;? Should you be led by the numbers in your business buying and selling decisions? Let&#8217;s deal with that today. Having previously bought various properties, I&#8217;m now considering selling one A selling or buying decision around any asset, including property, or a business is a lot of the same sort [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/make-confident-business-decisions-should-you-follow-the-numbers/">Make Confident business decisions: should you &#8220;Follow the numbers&#8221;?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/make-confident-business-decisions-should-you-follow-the-numbers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Should_entrepreneurs_always_Follow_the_numbers_.mp3" length="7596676" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Should entrepreneurs always &quot;Follow the numbers&quot;?     Should you be led by the numbers in your business buying and selling decisions? Let&#039;s deal with that today.    Having previously bought various properties,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Should entrepreneurs always "Follow the numbers"?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
 Should you be led by the numbers in your business buying and selling decisions? Let's deal with that today.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Having previously bought various properties, I'm now considering selling one A selling or buying decision around any asset, including property, or a business is a lot of the same sort of thing.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
So you're buying an asset or selling an asset, which has a capital value, and then it will, if it works well, generate cashflow, sometimes negative if you get it wrong.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
So should you be led by the numbers?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
I've been on a train with a Google sheet, working out the capital gains of selling a residential property versus keeping it.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
What's interesting is how one arrives at decisions in business the nice thing about business is numbers guide you. Should they lead you? Should they guide you? Should you ignore them?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Let's take one extreme at a time and examine how it works.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Thesis: Ignore numbers (go with your gut)<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Extreme number one is to ignore the numbers and go with your guts, follow your intuition.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
There's a difference, between your guts and immediate instinct.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Instinctive reaction to pain causes short-term decisions<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Running a business or owning property.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Can be painful. , there's legal liability people hassling you, spending your own money and time and regulations always increasing. Both in business and residential property. My experience in the uk, Amazon selling is not getting any less full of regulations particularly if you sell in the eu or you know, if you're looking at Amazon's legal changes.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Okay, so gut reaction might be just sell the damn thing because it's painful, but anything worthwhile can be painful. That's probably not a good plan.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Now, what about intuition? If your intuition says, it's hard work, but the pain is not worth the gain. You might be right. Intuition can, misguide us because we overrate immediate pain and underwrite future pain. So if we do something now that makes them the easy but cost you a lot of pain in the future, that's not a very rational way of making decisions.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Pure instinct or intuition has its dangers. So in the pure form, probably unwise, although one should not ignore one's intuition as an entrepreneur, <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Antithesis: Being led purely by the numbers<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Here's version two, led by the numbers, not guided by the numbers, but just led by them.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The classic example of that mistake is in the the lockdown period or just after that, a lot of aggregators, private equity companies with a lot of money went out shopping for e commerce businesses based on Amazon. They made multiple mistakes, but one of them was based simply on following the numbers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
A lot of very smart people, many of whom I interviewed for the podcast at the time, were involved in that, but they didn't have Amazon common sense or e commerce common sense they were good at, number analysis. So they analyzed the numbers but what they didn't take out was any kind of common sense.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Why did the aggregators get it wrong in 2021-22?<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
If you look at the root cause of the massive increase in revenue and profits of e commerce businesses around 2019, 2020, was obvious. The pandemic and lockdowns particularly in the UK and US. Were extreme.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
I was in the UK at the time, so yeah, that is in retrospect, I guess, very obvious what was, was going on there.]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>01</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>01</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>608</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>608</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>7:55</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">15059</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AI Finances for Amazon &amp; eCommerce Sellers</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/ai-finances-for-amazon-ecommerce-sellers/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/ai-finances-for-amazon-ecommerce-sellers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Imagine you&#8217;re a thriving Amazon seller. You log in to Seller Central, download your settlement report, and receive your net deposit. But here&#8217;s the catch: the numbers don&#8217;t quite paint a clear picture of your finances. Amazon reserves make understanding your true profit, profitability, and cash flow a challenge. Now, add multiple sales channels to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/ai-finances-for-amazon-ecommerce-sellers/">AI Finances for Amazon &amp; eCommerce Sellers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/ai-finances-for-amazon-ecommerce-sellers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/E02-AI_in_Accounting_for_Amazon_sellers-auphonic.mp3" length="16847515" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Imagine you&#039;re a thriving Amazon seller. You log in to Seller Central, download your settlement report, and receive your net deposit. But here&#039;s the catch: the numbers don&#039;t quite paint a clear picture of your finances.</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Imagine you're a thriving Amazon seller. You log in to Seller Central, download your settlement report, and receive your net deposit. But here's the catch: the numbers don't quite paint a clear picture of your finances. Amazon reserves make understanding your true profit, profitability, and cash flow a challenge.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Now, add multiple sales channels to the mix. The complexity grows exponentially, leaving you scrambling to reconcile data and make sense of your finances. This is where AI-powered accounting steps in, offering a lifeline for busy eCommerce brand owners.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00] - Importance Of Clean Data For Business Owners[00:44] - Introduction And Context Setting[01:07] - Challenges Of Single-Channel Amazon Selling[02:10] - Webgility's Data Integration Process[03:02] - Multi-Channel Data Consolidation[03:38] - AI Assistant's Role In Data Analysis[04:34] - Automating Data Transfer To Accounting Systems[05:16] - Computers' Efficiency In Numerical Calculations[05:59] - Common Issues In Data Integration[06:20] - Importance Of Consistent SKU Naming Conventions[07:31] - Webgility's Approach To Clean Data Setup[08:16] - Challenges Of Maintaining Consistent Data Practices[09:24] - Development Of AI-Powered Product Mapping Capabilities[10:40] - Difference Between Mechanical Systems And Intelligent Systems[11:58] - Two Approaches To Accounting Systems[13:39] - Impact Of Clean Books On Business Valuation[14:50] - Progression From Top-Line Focus To Profit And Valuation[15:17] - Introduction To Webgility's Services[16:10] - Webgility's Resources And Upcoming Webinars[16:39] - Importance Of Financial Preparation For Holiday Season[17:06] - Final Advice On Understanding Business Profitability[17:31] - Conclusion And Thank You<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
How AI Simplifies Your Accounting Nightmare<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Webgility leverages the power of AI to transform your eCommerce finances. It can handle data from the most granular level (SKU) to your overall settlement reports, all presented in a user-friendly, centralized dashboard. Going beyond Amazon, Webgility integrates with other platforms and payment processors, offering a comprehensive overview of your finances, regardless of your sales channels.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Imagine logging in and having a virtual assistant at your fingertips, ready to answer your financial questions. AI-powered tools allow you to seamlessly connect your data with popular accounting software like QuickBooks. This enables you to record granular-level fees, identify trends over time, and gain valuable insights, all within Webgility or directly in your accounting software.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Clean Data: The Foundation for Accurate Finances<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
But before diving into AI, let's address the elephant in the room: clean data. Garbage in, garbage out is still a golden rule in the digital age. No matter how powerful AI is, it can't magically transform messy data into financial clarity.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The key to success starts with a well-organized product catalog. Develop a consistent SKU naming convention across all your channels. This seemingly simple step ensures accurate sales and profit tracking over time. Remember, inconsistent data leads to inaccurate reports, hindering your ability to make informed decisions.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
While AI excels at processing unstructured data, it's not a miracle solution.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Here's where Webgility shines. It helps you get started the right way by offering features like:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* SKU naming guidance: Webgility assists in establishing a consistent naming convention for your catalog.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* On-the-fly account creation: Streamline the process by having Webgility automatically create clean accounts as you manage your business.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>607</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>607</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>AI Finances for Amazon &amp; eCommerce Sellers</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>17:33</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">15041</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Artificial Intelligence for Amazon &amp; eCommerce Sellers</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/artificial-intelligence-for-amazon-ecommerce-sellers/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/artificial-intelligence-for-amazon-ecommerce-sellers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=15040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In today&#8217;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, artificial intelligence (AI) has emerged as a game-changer for businesses of all sizes. For eCommerce sellers, AI offers a powerful tool to streamline operations, enhance customer experiences, and gain a competitive edge. This guide will delve into how SMB eCommerce businesses can leverage AI to optimize their operations, improve [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/artificial-intelligence-for-amazon-ecommerce-sellers/">Artificial Intelligence for Amazon &amp; eCommerce Sellers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/artificial-intelligence-for-amazon-ecommerce-sellers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/E01-AI_for_Amazon_ecommerce_sellers-auphonic.mp3" length="24428041" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>In today&#039;s rapidly evolving digital landscape, artificial intelligence (AI) has emerged as a game-changer for businesses of all sizes. For eCommerce sellers, AI offers a powerful tool to streamline operations, enhance customer experiences,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
In today's rapidly evolving digital landscape, artificial intelligence (AI) has emerged as a game-changer for businesses of all sizes. For eCommerce sellers, AI offers a powerful tool to streamline operations, enhance customer experiences, and gain a competitive edge. This guide will delve into how SMB eCommerce businesses can leverage AI to optimize their operations, improve decision-making, and achieve sustainable growth.  <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00] - AI Benefits For Business Owners And Consumers[01:01] - Introduction To The 10K Collective Podcast[01:45] - Parag Mamnani's Background And Founding Of Webgility[02:36] - Challenges Of Multi-Channel E-Commerce And Inventory Management[03:34] - Financial Systems As The Cleanest System Of Record[04:47] - Complexity Of Pricing And Inventory Tracking[06:00] - AI Adoption In E-Commerce Organizations[07:16] - Early Days Of AI Integration In E-Commerce Platforms[08:30] - Difference Between Generative AI And Regression-Based AI[09:45] - Barriers For SMBs In Adopting AI Technologies[11:29] - AI For Small Business Operations[12:42] - Bifurcation Of AI Technology In Business[14:29] - Key Capabilities Of AI Assistants In Business Operations[15:52] - Importance Of Predictive Power In AI For Business Decisions[17:16] - Challenges In Forecasting Due To Unpredictable Events[19:12] - Impact Of Black Swan Events On Predictions[20:31] - Limitations Of Forecasting For Small Businesses[22:03] - Factors For Successful Future Predictions In E-Commerce[23:38] - Importance Of Blending AI With Human Intuition[24:53] - AI Assistant Inclusion And Learning From Customer Expectations<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Understanding AI's Potential for eCommerce<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
AI, with its ability to analyze vast amounts of data and learn from patterns, can significantly benefit eCommerce sellers in various ways. By automating routine tasks, providing valuable insights, and personalizing customer experiences, AI can help businesses increase efficiency, reduce costs, and drive sales.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The Benefits of AI for eCommerce<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Enhanced Efficiency: AI can automate repetitive tasks such as order processing, inventory management, and customer service, freeing up valuable time for more strategic activities.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Improved Decision-Making: By analyzing data and identifying trends, AI can provide valuable insights to inform business decisions, such as pricing, marketing, and product development.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Personalized Customer Experiences: AI-powered recommendation engines can offer tailored product suggestions to customers, increasing engagement and loyalty.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Optimized Operations: AI can help streamline supply chain management, improve inventory forecasting, and optimize logistics, leading to cost savings and improved customer satisfaction.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Leveraging AI for Operational Excellence<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Inventory Management: AI can help optimize inventory levels by predicting demand, preventing stockouts, and reducing excess inventory costs.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Pricing Optimization: AI algorithms can analyze market data and competitor pricing to determine optimal pricing strategies, maximizing revenue and profitability.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Fulfillment and Logistics: AI can streamline the fulfillment process by optimizing shipping routes, reducing delivery times, and improving customer satisfaction.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Customer Service: AI-powered chatbots can provide instant customer support, answer common queries, and resolve issues efficiently.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Harnessing AI for Marketing and Sales<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Personalized Marketing: AI can help create targeted marketing campaigns based on customer preferences, demographics, and purchase history,]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>606</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>606</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Artificial Intelligence for Amazon &amp; eCommerce Sellers</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>25:27</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">15040</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Master the Art of Buyer Meetings: Step-by-Step Rapport Building Guide</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-crush-your-buyer-meeting-terrific-rapport-tips-step-5/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-crush-your-buyer-meeting-terrific-rapport-tips-step-5/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14979</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Congratulations! You&#8217;ve made it through the first four steps of successfully acquiring an e-commerce business to scale your brand. Here&#8217;s a quick recap: Now comes a crucial step: the buyer meeting. This is your chance to connect with the seller, build rapport, evaluate the business, and set the stage for a successful acquisition. This guide [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/how-to-crush-your-buyer-meeting-terrific-rapport-tips-step-5/">Master the Art of Buyer Meetings: Step-by-Step Rapport Building Guide</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/how-to-crush-your-buyer-meeting-terrific-rapport-tips-step-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/E01-How_to_crush_you_Buyer_meeting-Terrific_Rapport_Tips_Step_5-auphonic.mp3" length="16011597" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Congratulations! You&#039;ve made it through the first four steps of successfully acquiring an e-commerce business to scale your brand. Here&#039;s a quick recap:     Decide to Buy: Defined your goals and motivations for acquisition.    </itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Congratulations! You've made it through the first four steps of successfully acquiring an e-commerce business to scale your brand. Here's a quick recap:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Decide to Buy: Defined your goals and motivations for acquisition.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Define Your Ideal Target Business: Identified the type of business that aligns with your vision.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Find Your Ideal Businesses (Deal Flow): Utilized various strategies to discover potential acquisition targets.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Filter Your Suspects to Prospects: Narrowed down your options to qualified candidates.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Now comes a crucial step: the buyer meeting. This is your chance to connect with the seller, build rapport, evaluate the business, and set the stage for a successful acquisition. This guide will equip you with the tools and strategies to navigate this pivotal step.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Time Stamp<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:44] - Introduction To 10 Step Process For Acquiring E-commerce Business[01:03] - Recap Of Previous Steps[01:59] - Four Aims Of Step Five[02:43] - Importance Of Building Rapport[03:42] - Evaluating The Business[04:42] - Preparation Before The Meeting[05:30] - Researching The Business And Owner[06:30] - Basics For The Meeting: Dress Code And Punctuality[07:45] - Managing Meeting Time[08:44] - Main Aim In The Meeting: Building Rapport[09:31] - Active Listening Techniques[10:48] - Balancing Professionalism And Friendliness[11:27] - Presenting Your Own Value[12:26] - Positioning Yourself As An Experienced Dealmaker[13:20] - Offer To Review Potential Deals[13:35] - Importance Of First Impressions And Rapport Building[14:39] - Practice Makes Perfect: Role Playing And Reflection[15:14] - Offer For Assistance In Business Buying Process[16:32] - Preview Of Next Episode: Six Killer Questions<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Aims of this Step in the Process:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Building Rapport: Create a connection and establish trust with the seller.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Positioning Yourself as an Expert/Safe Pair of Hands: Demonstrate your knowledge and capability to manage the business.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Evaluating the Business: Gain a deeper understanding of the company's strengths and weaknesses.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Setting Up Next Steps: Determine a clear path forward for moving towards acquisition talks.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Overview of the Process:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This section will delve into the key aspects of your buyer meeting:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Preparation: How to gather information and prepare yourself for the encounter.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Setting the Right Tone: Ensuring professionalism and creating a comfortable environment.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Building Rapport: Techniques to connect with the seller on a personal level.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Evaluating the Business: Strategies for acquiring a basic understanding of the company's performance.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Setting Up Next Steps: Establishing a clear plan for moving forward.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Preparation (3 minutes):<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Before the meeting, thorough preparation is key. Here's how to hit the ground running:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
A. Researching the Business and Owner:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Owner:<br />
<br />
* LinkedIn: Explore their experience, network, and any connections you might share.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Google: Look for news articles, interviews, or past ventures that demonstrate their expertise.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Facebook: Gain insights into their interests and personality (optional).<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Business:<br />
<br />
* Amazon: Analyze the listings, pricing strategy, reviews, and customer engagement.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>591</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>591</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Master the Art of Buyer Meetings: Step-by-Step Rapport Building Guide</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>16:41</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14979</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Reasons To Use Custom Shipping Boxes</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/4-reasons-to-use-custom-shipping-boxes/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/4-reasons-to-use-custom-shipping-boxes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 15:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Packaging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shipping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shipping cartons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Investing in custom shipping boxes can bring numerous benefits to your business. While it may seem that using standard sizes and styles is more cost-effective, if the boxes are not a perfect fit for their contents, there&#8217;s a high possibility that the contents won&#8217;t be as protected as they need to be. This could lead [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/4-reasons-to-use-custom-shipping-boxes/">4 Reasons To Use Custom Shipping Boxes</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/4-reasons-to-use-custom-shipping-boxes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14883</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Avoiding Layoffs with 4 Proven Methods</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/avoiding-layoffs-with-4-proven-methods/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/avoiding-layoffs-with-4-proven-methods/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 15:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[team]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Layoffs are never fun, but sometimes avoiding layoffs seems impossible. After all, paying competitive salaries to your staff is hardly all you need to spend to keep people around. You need insurance, training measures, daily resources, functional utilities, and equipment. All of that, of course, tends to pay for itself given the hard work of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/avoiding-layoffs-with-4-proven-methods/">Avoiding Layoffs with 4 Proven Methods</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/avoiding-layoffs-with-4-proven-methods/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14879</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is your Amazon business really worth what you think it is?</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/is-your-amazon-business-really-worth-what-you-think-it-is/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/is-your-amazon-business-really-worth-what-you-think-it-is/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey, Amazing FBA]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 10:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14854</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Your Amazon business -that is to say, an e-commerce business based on Amazon as the main sales channel- is a sellable business. That’s the good news. The bad news is that the way you think of your business -and structure your profit and loss- may be deluding you into thinking it’s worth more than it [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/is-your-amazon-business-really-worth-what-you-think-it-is/">Is your Amazon business really worth what you think it is?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/is-your-amazon-business-really-worth-what-you-think-it-is/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Are_you_kidding_yourself_about_the_value_of_your_e-commerce_business_Auphonic.mp3" length="11523995" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Your Amazon business -that is to say, an e-commerce business based on Amazon as the main sales channel- is a sellable business. That’s the good news. The bad news is that the way you think of your business -and structure your profit and loss- may be de...</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Your Amazon business -that is to say, an e-commerce business based on Amazon as the main sales channel- is a sellable business. That’s the good news. The bad news is that the way you think of your business -and structure your profit and loss- may be deluding you into thinking it’s worth more than it is. Listen to today’s podcast for a reality check on small business valuation! <br />]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>574</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>574</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>13:43</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14854</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Skip the Startup Hustle: 10 Reasons to Acquire a Profitable E-commerce Business</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/acquire-profitable-ecommerce-business/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/acquire-profitable-ecommerce-business/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Have you poured your heart and soul into building your e-commerce brand, but feel the pressure to scale without breaking the bank? Starting a new venture from scratch can be exhilarating, but it&#8217;s also a risky and time-consuming process. Fortunately, there&#8217;s another path to achieve your growth goals – acquiring an existing e-commerce business. This [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/acquire-profitable-ecommerce-business/">Skip the Startup Hustle: 10 Reasons to Acquire a Profitable E-commerce Business</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/acquire-profitable-ecommerce-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Episode_01-10_Reasons_to_buy_an_e-commerce_business-auphonic.mp3" length="12892368" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>Have you poured your heart and soul into building your e-commerce brand, but feel the pressure to scale without breaking the bank? Starting a new venture from scratch can be exhilarating, but it&#039;s also a risky and time-consuming process. Fortunately,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
Have you poured your heart and soul into building your e-commerce brand, but feel the pressure to scale without breaking the bank? Starting a new venture from scratch can be exhilarating, but it's also a risky and time-consuming process. Fortunately, there's another path to achieve your growth goals – acquiring an existing e-commerce business.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
This approach offers a wealth of advantages, allowing you to leverage a proven model, established customer base, and existing revenue streams, all without the typical startup struggles. Let's delve into the top 10 reasons why acquiring a profitable e-commerce business might be the perfect strategy for scaling your brand efficiently.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:29] - Promotion for 10K Collective Mastermind[00:52] - Reasons to buy an e-commerce business[01:27] - Buying an established profitable business[02:12] - E-commerce is scalable[02:54] - Low overhead costs in e-commerce[03:34] - Access to existing infrastructure[04:12] - E-commerce growth potential in the U.S.[05:39] - Potential for automation in e-commerce[06:25] - Diversification across markets[07:08] - Can you afford to buy a business?[09:07] - Upcoming mini-series on buying a business[09:52] - Offer to evaluate potential acquisitions[10:14] - Benefits of an acquisition mindset<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
1. Established Brand and Customer Base: Hit the Ground Running<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Building brand recognition and acquiring loyal customers takes time and significant marketing efforts. By acquiring an established e-commerce business, you inherit a ready-made audience – a crucial advantage in the competitive world of online retail. You'll benefit from existing brand awareness, customer trust, and a pool of loyal repeat buyers, allowing you to focus on growing the business rather than starting from scratch. This existing customer base also provides valuable insights into market preferences and purchasing behavior, which can inform your future marketing strategies.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
2. Proven Business Model: Reduce Risk and Leverage Success<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
The e-commerce landscape is dynamic and ever-changing. When you build a business from the ground up, you're essentially embarking on an experiment. By acquiring an established e-commerce business, you're inheriting a proven business model that has already demonstrated success. You'll gain access to a roadmap for success, including established product lines, marketing strategies, and operational processes that are demonstrably effective. This not only reduces the inherent risks associated with starting a new venture, but also provides a framework for future growth and optimization.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
3. Existing Revenue Stream: Start Profiting Today<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
One of the most significant challenges new businesses face is establishing a steady cash flow. When you acquire an existing e-commerce business, you gain immediate access to an established revenue stream. This allows you to offset the initial investment cost more quickly, reinvest in growth initiatives, and start generating profits from day one. This financial stability provides a solid foundation for future expansion and allows you to make strategic decisions with greater confidence.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
4. Scalability Potential: Built for Growth in the Digital Age<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
E-commerce businesses are inherently scalable, offering significant growth potential compared to traditional brick-and-mortar stores. With a well-established online presence, you can easily expand your product offerings, target new markets, and reach a wider audience. Unlike physical retail, geographical limitations are virtually non-existent. You can leverage digital marketing channels to reach customers across the globe, increasing brand visibility and driving sales. Additionally, e-commerce platforms often offer built-in scaling features,]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>570</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>570</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Skip the Startup Hustle: 10 Reasons to Acquire a Profitable E-commerce Business</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>13:26</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14823</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SMS vs Email Marketing for Amazon Sellers: Which is Right for You?</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/sms-vs-email-marketing-amazon-sellers/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/sms-vs-email-marketing-amazon-sellers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the cutthroat world of e-commerce, maximizing customer engagement is paramount. Yet, with a plethora of marketing channels available, choosing the right one can be daunting. This guide delves into the powerhouses of email and SMS marketing, specifically for Amazon sellers on a budget, helping you decide which weapon best suits your brand&#8217;s arsenal. [00:00:00] [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/sms-vs-email-marketing-amazon-sellers/">SMS vs Email Marketing for Amazon Sellers: Which is Right for You?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/sms-vs-email-marketing-amazon-sellers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Episode_02-Nikita_Vakhrushev-auphonic.mp3" length="23178343" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>In the cutthroat world of e-commerce, maximizing customer engagement is paramount. Yet, with a plethora of marketing channels available, choosing the right one can be daunting. This guide delves into the powerhouses of email and SMS marketing,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
In the cutthroat world of e-commerce, maximizing customer engagement is paramount. Yet, with a plethora of marketing channels available, choosing the right one can be daunting. This guide delves into the powerhouses of email and SMS marketing, specifically for Amazon sellers on a budget, helping you decide which weapon best suits your brand's arsenal.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:00:00] - You Can Set Up Future Sends for Most Impact[00:00:26] - Introducing the 10K Collective Uber Mastermind[00:00:49] - Discussing Email Marketing Segmentation and Flows[00:01:22] - Importance of Email Marketing for Sales[00:02:18] - Dos and Don'ts for Email Design and Content[00:04:20] - Best Times to Send Email Campaigns[00:05:20] - Weekday vs Weekend Email Sending[00:06:39] - Using SMS Marketing in Addition to Email[00:09:00] - Revenue Impact of SMS Marketing Campaigns[00:10:30] - SMS Marketing Cost Considerations[00:11:36] - Shelf Life of SMS Numbers for Marketing[00:13:35] - Re-Engaging Neglected Email Lists[00:15:16] - Setting Up Email and SMS Marketing Structure[00:17:03] - Avoiding Overattribution with Multiple Platforms[00:18:03] - Integrating SMS Marketing Setup Process[00:19:03] - Services Offered by Aspect Agency[00:20:28] - Getting a Free Email Marketing Audit[00:21:26] - Any Questions for the Email Marketing Expert[00:22:00] - Introducing the 10K Collective Uber Mastermind[00:23:49] - Closing Thoughts<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Email Marketing: A Powerful Foundation<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Email marketing remains a cornerstone of e-commerce success. Here's why:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Cost-Effective: Reaching thousands of customers with a single email is incredibly affordable.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Scalability: Your email list can grow exponentially, allowing for broader reach.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Content Versatility: Tailor emails with captivating visuals, informative content, and personalized offers.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Automation Magic: Set up automated email sequences to nurture leads and drive sales efficiently.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Avoiding Common Email Marketing Blunders<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Even the most potent tool can backfire if used incorrectly. Here are some email marketing pitfalls to avoid:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Buried Lead Syndrome: Don't hide crucial information below the fold.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Image Overload: While visuals are valuable, prioritize clear communication over aesthetics.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* MIA Information: Clearly state the email's purpose, be it a product launch, promotion, or valuable resource.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Link Overload: Excessive links can trigger spam filters. Keep it concise and focused.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Image Size Issues: Use tools like TinyPNG to optimize image size for faster loading times.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Optimizing Your Email Send Times<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Timing is crucial for email marketing success. Unfortunately, a one-size-fits-all approach doesn't exist. Consider A/B testing on platforms like Klaviyo to determine the best send times for your audience. Here are some general best practices:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Pre-Work Hours: 7-8 AM often catches people checking emails before starting their day.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Lunchtime Lull: 11 AM-1 PM can be a good time for browsing promotions.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Post-Work Window: 6-8 PM caters to those catching up after work.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Weekend Strategy: While weekends can be hit-or-miss, Saturday mornings might work for specific sales or promotions. Sundays are generally best avoided.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
SMS Marketing: The Powerhouse of Personalization<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
SMS marketing boasts unique advantages:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* High Open Rates: SMS messages often boast open rates exceeding 90%,]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>568</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>568</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>SMS vs Email Marketing for Amazon Sellers: Which is Right for You?</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>24:09</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14809</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dominate Your Niche: Build an Email List for Amazon Sellers Like a Pro</title>
		<link>https://amazingfba.com/build-email-list-amazon-sellers/</link>
					<comments>https://amazingfba.com/build-email-list-amazon-sellers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael Veazey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Running An Ecommerce Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10K Collective Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazing FBA Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://amazingfba.com/?p=14805</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>E-commerce success on Amazon is fantastic, but it&#8217;s like renting a storefront. You don&#8217;t own the customer data, limiting your ability to build brand loyalty and scale beyond the platform. This is where email marketing shines. In this guide, we&#8217;ll equip you, the savvy Amazon seller, to build a thriving email list and unlock explosive [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://amazingfba.com/build-email-list-amazon-sellers/">Dominate Your Niche: Build an Email List for Amazon Sellers Like a Pro</a> appeared first on <a href="https://amazingfba.com">Amazing FBA - Grow your 7-Figure Amazon Business</a>.</p>
]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>https://amazingfba.com/build-email-list-amazon-sellers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		<enclosure url="https://media.blubrry.com/amazingfba/content.blubrry.com/amazingfba/Episode_01-Nikita_Vakhrushev-auphonic.mp3" length="31303888" type="audio/mpeg" />

			<itunes:subtitle>E-commerce success on Amazon is fantastic, but it&#039;s like renting a storefront. You don&#039;t own the customer data, limiting your ability to build brand loyalty and scale beyond the platform. This is where email marketing shines. In this guide,</itunes:subtitle>
		<itunes:summary><![CDATA[<br />
E-commerce success on Amazon is fantastic, but it's like renting a storefront. You don't own the customer data, limiting your ability to build brand loyalty and scale beyond the platform. This is where email marketing shines. In this guide, we'll equip you, the savvy Amazon seller, to build a thriving email list and unlock explosive growth for your brand – all with minimal capital.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
[00:01:19] - Discussing Email Marketing with Expert Nikita[00:02:07] - Email Marketing Relevance for Amazon Sellers[00:03:11] - Getting Customer Data from Amazon Orders[00:04:22] - Using Landing Pages for Email List Building[00:05:09] - Avoiding Amazon's Buy Box Suppression[00:06:07] - Offering Mysterious Discounts for Email Opt-Ins[00:07:21] - Effective Opt-In Rates for Email Capture[00:09:08] - Email Marketing vs List Building Strategies[00:10:01] - Setting Up Website Pop-Ups for Email Capture[00:11:15] - Welcome Email Flow for New Subscribers[00:12:16] - Using Quizzes for Email Capture and Segmentation[00:13:35] - Importance of Email List Segmentation[00:15:25] - Using Suppression Lists for Better Deliverability[00:17:27] - Cleaning Email Lists to Reduce Costs[00:19:04] - Core Email Flows and Automations to Set Up[00:21:49] - Cross-Selling Strategies via Email Marketing[00:24:13] - Tracking Revenue from Email Marketing Efforts[00:30:28] - Introducing the 10K Collective Uber Mastermind<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Why Email Marketing Matters for Amazon Sellers<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Nikita, CEO of ASPEKT, a powerhouse email and SMS marketing agency, emphasizes the transformative power of email marketing, especially for hybrid brands utilizing both Amazon and DTC channels. While Amazon provides a launchpad, email marketing empowers you to cultivate direct customer relationships, fostering brand loyalty and repeat purchases.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Here's how email marketing becomes your secret weapon:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Capture customer data you can't access on Amazon. Though Amazon guards customer emails fiercely, you can utilize product inserts and other creative strategies to collect valuable contact information.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Retarget potential customers based on browsing behavior. Leverage ad platforms to reconnect with those who expressed interest in your products but didn't convert on Amazon.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Break free from the buy box trap. Offer exclusive discounts or mystery offers via email, enticing customers to bypass the competitive buy box scenario.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Mystery sells! Intrigue trumps generic discounts. Pique customer curiosity with mystery offers, driving them to your email list for the big reveal.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Building Your Email List Beyond Amazon<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Now, let's dive into the nitty-gritty of building your email list:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Strategic website popups: Capture email addresses strategically. Consider popups triggered by 50% page scrolling or after 10-20 seconds on your site.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Mystery offer magic: Fuel sign-ups with a captivating mystery offer that sparks curiosity and begs for email subscription.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Crafting Core Flows for Email Marketing Success<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
A well-structured email sequence is the backbone of a winning DTC email strategy. Let's explore some essential flows:<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Welcome Flow: This is your first impression! Set the tone with a warm welcome email, including a discount code and a brand story that resonates with your target audience.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Value-Driven Content: Go beyond the sale. Provide valuable content tailored to your niche. For example, fashion brands can offer styling tips, while food brands can share delicious recipes.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
* Personalized Product Recommendations: Leverage quizzes to unde...]]></itunes:summary>
		<itunes:author>Michael Veazey</itunes:author>
		<itunes:image href="https://amazingfba.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Amazing-FBA-PODCAST-ARTWORK-redesign-v4.2-with-10k-text-Amazing-in-Abril-FBA-in-Abril-Blue-words.jpg" />
		<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
		<podcast:season>1</podcast:season>
		<itunes:episode>567</itunes:episode>
		<podcast:episode>567</podcast:episode>
		<itunes:title>Dominate Your Niche: Build an Email List for Amazon Sellers Like a Pro</itunes:title>
		<itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
		<itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
		<itunes:duration>32:36</itunes:duration>
<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14805</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
